<document>
  <filename>D12-1027</filename>
  <authors>
    <author>Pidong Wang</author>
    <author>Preslav Nakov</author>
  </authors>
  <title>Source Language Adaptation for Resource-Poor Machine Translation</title>
  <content>
    <sections>
      <section>
        <index>0</index>
        <title>Abstract</title>
        <text>We propose a novel, language-independent approach for improving machine translation from a resource-poor language to X by adapting a large bi-text for a related resource-rich language and X (the same target language). We assume a small bi-text for the resourcepoor language to X pair, which we use to learn word-level and phrase-level paraphrases and cross-lingual morphological variants between the resource-rich and the resource-poor language; we then adapt the former to get closer to the latter. Our experiments for Indonesian/Malay&#8211;English translation show that using the large adapted resource-rich bitext yields 6.7 BLEU points of improvement over the unadapted one and 2.6 BLEU points over the original small bi-text. Moreover, combining the small bi-text with the adapted bi-text outperforms the corresponding combinations with the unadapted bi-text by 1.5&#8211; 3 BLEU points. We also demonstrate applicability to other languages and domains.</text>
        <paragraphs>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>We propose a novel, language-independent approach for improving machine translation from a resource-poor language to X by adapting a large bi-text for a related resource-rich language and X (the same target language).</text>
              <doc_id>0</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>We assume a small bi-text for the resourcepoor language to X pair, which we use to learn word-level and phrase-level paraphrases and cross-lingual morphological variants between the resource-rich and the resource-poor language; we then adapt the former to get closer to the latter.</text>
              <doc_id>1</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Our experiments for Indonesian/Malay&#8211;English translation show that using the large adapted resource-rich bitext yields 6.7 BLEU points of improvement over the unadapted one and 2.6 BLEU points over the original small bi-text.</text>
              <doc_id>2</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Moreover, combining the small bi-text with the adapted bi-text outperforms the corresponding combinations with the unadapted bi-text by 1.5&#8211; 3 BLEU points.</text>
              <doc_id>3</doc_id>
              <sec_id>3</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>We also demonstrate applicability to other languages and domains.</text>
              <doc_id>4</doc_id>
              <sec_id>4</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
        </paragraphs>
        <subsections/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <index>1</index>
        <title>1 Introduction</title>
        <text>Statistical machine translation (SMT) systems learn how to translate from large sentence-aligned bilingual corpora of human-generated translations, called bi-texts. Unfortunately, collecting sufficiently large, high-quality bi-texts is hard, and thus most of the 6,500+ world languages remain resource-poor. Fortunately, many of these resource-poor languages are related to some resource-rich language, with whom they overlap in vocabulary and share cognates, which offers opportunities for bi-text reuse. Example pairs of such resource rich&#8211;poor languages include Spanish&#8211;Catalan, Finnish&#8211;Estonian, Swedish&#8211;Norwegian, Russian&#8211;Ukrainian, Irish&#8211; Gaelic Scottish, Standard German&#8211;Swiss German, Modern Standard Arabic&#8211;Dialectical Arabic (e.g., Gulf, Egyptian), Turkish&#8211;Azerbaijani, etc.
Previous work has already demonstrated the benefits of using a bi-text for a related resource-rich language to X (e.g., X=English) to improve machine translation from a resource-poor language to X (Nakov and Ng, 2009; Nakov and Ng, 2012). Here we take a different, orthogonal approach: we adapt the resource-rich language to get closer to the resource-poor one.
We assume a small bi-text for the resource-poor language, which we use to learn word-level and phrase-level paraphrases and cross-lingual morphological variants between the two languages. Assuming translation into the same target language X, we adapt (the source side of) a large training bi-text for a related resource-rich language and X.
Training on the adapted large bi-text yields very significant improvements in translation quality compared to both (a) training on the unadapted version, and (b) training on the small bi-text for the resourcepoor language. We further achieve very sizable improvements when combining the small bi-text with the large adapted bi-text, compared to combining the former with the unadapted bi-text.
While we focus on adapting Malay to look like Indonesian in our experiments, we also demonstrate the applicability of our approach to another language pair, Bulgarian&#8211;Macedonian, which is also from a different domain.</text>
        <paragraphs>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>Statistical machine translation (SMT) systems learn how to translate from large sentence-aligned bilingual corpora of human-generated translations, called bi-texts.</text>
              <doc_id>5</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Unfortunately, collecting sufficiently large, high-quality bi-texts is hard, and thus most of the 6,500+ world languages remain resource-poor.</text>
              <doc_id>6</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Fortunately, many of these resource-poor languages are related to some resource-rich language, with whom they overlap in vocabulary and share cognates, which offers opportunities for bi-text reuse.</text>
              <doc_id>7</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Example pairs of such resource rich&#8211;poor languages include Spanish&#8211;Catalan, Finnish&#8211;Estonian, Swedish&#8211;Norwegian, Russian&#8211;Ukrainian, Irish&#8211; Gaelic Scottish, Standard German&#8211;Swiss German, Modern Standard Arabic&#8211;Dialectical Arabic (e.g., Gulf, Egyptian), Turkish&#8211;Azerbaijani, etc.</text>
              <doc_id>8</doc_id>
              <sec_id>3</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>Previous work has already demonstrated the benefits of using a bi-text for a related resource-rich language to X (e.g., X=English) to improve machine translation from a resource-poor language to X (Nakov and Ng, 2009; Nakov and Ng, 2012).</text>
              <doc_id>9</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Here we take a different, orthogonal approach: we adapt the resource-rich language to get closer to the resource-poor one.</text>
              <doc_id>10</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>We assume a small bi-text for the resource-poor language, which we use to learn word-level and phrase-level paraphrases and cross-lingual morphological variants between the two languages.</text>
              <doc_id>11</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Assuming translation into the same target language X, we adapt (the source side of) a large training bi-text for a related resource-rich language and X.</text>
              <doc_id>12</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>Training on the adapted large bi-text yields very significant improvements in translation quality compared to both (a) training on the unadapted version, and (b) training on the small bi-text for the resourcepoor language.</text>
              <doc_id>13</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>We further achieve very sizable improvements when combining the small bi-text with the large adapted bi-text, compared to combining the former with the unadapted bi-text.</text>
              <doc_id>14</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>While we focus on adapting Malay to look like Indonesian in our experiments, we also demonstrate the applicability of our approach to another language pair, Bulgarian&#8211;Macedonian, which is also from a different domain.</text>
              <doc_id>15</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
        </paragraphs>
        <subsections/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <index>2</index>
        <title>2 Related Work</title>
        <text>One relevant line of research is on machine translation between closely related languages, which is arguably simpler than general SMT, and thus can be handled using word-for-word translation, manual language-specific rules that take care of the necessary morphological and syntactic transformations, or character-level translation/transliteration. This has been tried for a number of language pairs including Czech&#8211;Slovak (Haji&#269; et al., 2000), Turkish&#8211; Crimean Tatar (Altintas and Cicekli, 2002), Irish&#8211; Scottish Gaelic (Scannell, 2006), and Bulgarian&#8211; Macedonian (Nakov and Tiedemann, 2012). In contrast, we have a different objective &#8211; we do not carry out full translation but rather adaptation since our ultimate goal is to translate into a third language X.
A special case of this same line of research is the translation between dialects of the same language, e.g., between Cantonese and Mandarin (Zhang, 1998), or between a dialect of a language and a standard version of that language, e.g., between some Arabic dialect (e.g., Egyptian) and Modern Standard Arabic (Bakr et al., 2008; Sawaf, 2010; Salloum and Habash, 2011). Here again, manual rules and/or language-specific tools are typically used. In the case of Arabic dialects, a further complication arises by the informal status of the dialects, which are not standardized and not used in formal contexts but rather only in informal online communities 1 such as social networks, chats, Twitter and SMS messages. This causes further mismatch in domain and genre.
Thus, translating from Arabic dialects to Modern Standard Arabic requires, among other things, normalizing informal text to a formal form. In fact, this is a more general problem, which arises with informal sources like SMS messages and Tweets for just any language (Aw et al., 2006; Han and Baldwin, 2011). Here the main focus is on coping with spelling errors, abbreviations, and slang, which are typically addressed using string edit distance, while also taking pronunciation into account. This is different from our task, where we try to adapt good, formal text from one language into another.
A second relevant line of research is on language adaptation and normalization, when done specifically for improving SMT into another language.
1 The Egyptian Wikipedia is one notable exception.
For example, Marujo et al. (2011) described a rule-based system for adapting Brazilian Portuguese (BP) to European Portuguese (EP), which they used to adapt BP&#8211;English bi-texts to EP&#8211;English. They report small improvements in BLEU for EP&#8211;English translation when training on the adapted &#8220;EP&#8221;&#8211;En bi-text compared to using the unadapted BP&#8211;En (38.55 vs. 38.29), or when an EP&#8211;English bi-text is used in addition to the adapted/unadapted one (41.07 vs. 40.91 BLEU). Unlike this work, which heavily relied on language-specific rules, our approach is statistical, and largely language-independent; moreover, our improvements are much more sizable.
A third relevant line of research is on reusing bitexts between related languages without or with very little adaptation, which works well for very closely related languages. For example, our previous work (Nakov and Ng, 2009; Nakov and Ng, 2012) experimented with various techniques for combining a small bi-text for a resource-poor language (Indonesian or Spanish, pretending that Spanish is resource-poor) with a much larger bi-text for a related resource-rich language (Malay or Portuguese); the target language of all bi-texts was English. However, our previous work did not attempt language adaptation, except for very simple transliteration for Portuguese&#8211;Spanish that ignored context entirely; since it could not substitute one word for a completely different word, it did not help much for Malay&#8211;Indonesian, which use unified spelling. Still, once we have language-adapted the large bi-text, it makes sense to try to combine it further with the small bi-text; thus, below we will directly compare and combine these two approaches.
Another alternative, which we do not explore in this work, is to use cascaded translation using a pivot language (Utiyama and Isahara, 2007; Cohn and Lapata, 2007; Wu and Wang, 2009). Unfortunately, using the resource-rich language as a pivot (poor&#8594;rich&#8594;X) would require an additional parallel poor&#8211;rich bi-text, which we do not have. Pivoting over the target X (rich&#8594;X&#8594;poor) for the purpose of language adaptation, on the other hand, would miss the opportunity to exploit the relationship between the resource-poor and the resource-rich language; this would also be circular since the first step would ask an SMT system to translate its own training data (we only have one rich&#8211;X bi-text).</text>
        <paragraphs>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>One relevant line of research is on machine translation between closely related languages, which is arguably simpler than general SMT, and thus can be handled using word-for-word translation, manual language-specific rules that take care of the necessary morphological and syntactic transformations, or character-level translation/transliteration.</text>
              <doc_id>16</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>This has been tried for a number of language pairs including Czech&#8211;Slovak (Haji&#269; et al., 2000), Turkish&#8211; Crimean Tatar (Altintas and Cicekli, 2002), Irish&#8211; Scottish Gaelic (Scannell, 2006), and Bulgarian&#8211; Macedonian (Nakov and Tiedemann, 2012).</text>
              <doc_id>17</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>In contrast, we have a different objective &#8211; we do not carry out full translation but rather adaptation since our ultimate goal is to translate into a third language X.</text>
              <doc_id>18</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>A special case of this same line of research is the translation between dialects of the same language, e.g., between Cantonese and Mandarin (Zhang, 1998), or between a dialect of a language and a standard version of that language, e.g., between some Arabic dialect (e.g., Egyptian) and Modern Standard Arabic (Bakr et al., 2008; Sawaf, 2010; Salloum and Habash, 2011).</text>
              <doc_id>19</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Here again, manual rules and/or language-specific tools are typically used.</text>
              <doc_id>20</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>In the case of Arabic dialects, a further complication arises by the informal status of the dialects, which are not standardized and not used in formal contexts but rather only in informal online communities 1 such as social networks, chats, Twitter and SMS messages.</text>
              <doc_id>21</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>This causes further mismatch in domain and genre.</text>
              <doc_id>22</doc_id>
              <sec_id>3</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>Thus, translating from Arabic dialects to Modern Standard Arabic requires, among other things, normalizing informal text to a formal form.</text>
              <doc_id>23</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>In fact, this is a more general problem, which arises with informal sources like SMS messages and Tweets for just any language (Aw et al., 2006; Han and Baldwin, 2011).</text>
              <doc_id>24</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Here the main focus is on coping with spelling errors, abbreviations, and slang, which are typically addressed using string edit distance, while also taking pronunciation into account.</text>
              <doc_id>25</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>This is different from our task, where we try to adapt good, formal text from one language into another.</text>
              <doc_id>26</doc_id>
              <sec_id>3</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>A second relevant line of research is on language adaptation and normalization, when done specifically for improving SMT into another language.</text>
              <doc_id>27</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>1 The Egyptian Wikipedia is one notable exception.</text>
              <doc_id>28</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>For example, Marujo et al. (2011) described a rule-based system for adapting Brazilian Portuguese (BP) to European Portuguese (EP), which they used to adapt BP&#8211;English bi-texts to EP&#8211;English.</text>
              <doc_id>29</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>They report small improvements in BLEU for EP&#8211;English translation when training on the adapted &#8220;EP&#8221;&#8211;En bi-text compared to using the unadapted BP&#8211;En (38.55 vs. 38.29), or when an EP&#8211;English bi-text is used in addition to the adapted/unadapted one (41.07 vs. 40.91 BLEU).</text>
              <doc_id>30</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Unlike this work, which heavily relied on language-specific rules, our approach is statistical, and largely language-independent; moreover, our improvements are much more sizable.</text>
              <doc_id>31</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>A third relevant line of research is on reusing bitexts between related languages without or with very little adaptation, which works well for very closely related languages.</text>
              <doc_id>32</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>For example, our previous work (Nakov and Ng, 2009; Nakov and Ng, 2012) experimented with various techniques for combining a small bi-text for a resource-poor language (Indonesian or Spanish, pretending that Spanish is resource-poor) with a much larger bi-text for a related resource-rich language (Malay or Portuguese); the target language of all bi-texts was English.</text>
              <doc_id>33</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>However, our previous work did not attempt language adaptation, except for very simple transliteration for Portuguese&#8211;Spanish that ignored context entirely; since it could not substitute one word for a completely different word, it did not help much for Malay&#8211;Indonesian, which use unified spelling.</text>
              <doc_id>34</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Still, once we have language-adapted the large bi-text, it makes sense to try to combine it further with the small bi-text; thus, below we will directly compare and combine these two approaches.</text>
              <doc_id>35</doc_id>
              <sec_id>3</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>Another alternative, which we do not explore in this work, is to use cascaded translation using a pivot language (Utiyama and Isahara, 2007; Cohn and Lapata, 2007; Wu and Wang, 2009).</text>
              <doc_id>36</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Unfortunately, using the resource-rich language as a pivot (poor&#8594;rich&#8594;X) would require an additional parallel poor&#8211;rich bi-text, which we do not have.</text>
              <doc_id>37</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Pivoting over the target X (rich&#8594;X&#8594;poor) for the purpose of language adaptation, on the other hand, would miss the opportunity to exploit the relationship between the resource-poor and the resource-rich language; this would also be circular since the first step would ask an SMT system to translate its own training data (we only have one rich&#8211;X bi-text).</text>
              <doc_id>38</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
        </paragraphs>
        <subsections/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <index>3</index>
        <title>3 Malay and Indonesian</title>
        <text>the Universal Declaration of Human Rights: 2 &#8226; Semua manusia dilahirkan bebas dan samarata dari segi kemuliaan dan hak-hak. Mereka mempunyai pemikiran dan perasaan hati dan hendaklah bertindak di antara satu sama lain dengan semangat persaudaraan. (Malay) &#8226; Semua orang dilahirkan merdeka dan mempunyai martabat
dan hak-hak yang sama. Mereka dikaruniai akal dan hati nurani dan hendaknya bergaul satu sama lain dalam semangat persaudaraan. (Indonesian) There is only 50% overlap at the word level, but the actual vocabulary overlap is much higher, e.g., there is only one word in the Malay text that does not exist in Indonesian: samarata (&#8216;equal&#8217;). Other differences are due to the use of different morphological forms, e.g., hendaklah vs. hendaknya (&#8216;conscience&#8217;), derivational variants of hendak (&#8216;want&#8217;). Of course, word choice in translation is often a matter of taste. Thus, we asked a native speaker of Indonesian to adapt the Malay version to Indonesian while preserving as many words as possible:
dan hak-hak yang sama. Mereka mempunyai pemikiran dan perasaan dan hendaklah bergaul satu sama lain dalam semangat persaudaraan. (Indonesian) 2 English: All human beings are born free and equal in dignity and rights. They are endowed with reason and conscience and should act towards one another in a spirit of brotherhood. Obtaining this latter version from the original Malay text requires three word-level operations: (1) deletion of dari, segi, (2) insertion of yang, sama, and (3) substitution of samarata with mempunyai. Unfortunately, we do not have parallel Malay- Indonesian text, which complicates the process of learning when to apply these operations. Thus, below we restrict our attention to the simplest and most common operation of word substitution only, leaving the other two 3 operations for future work. Note that word substitution is enough in many cases, e.g., it is all that is needed for the following Malay-Indonesian sentence pair: 4
&#8226; KDNK Malaysia dijangka cecah 8 peratus pada tahun 2010. &#8226; PDB Malaysia akan mencapai 8 persen pada tahun 2010.</text>
        <paragraphs>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>the Universal Declaration of Human Rights: 2 &#8226; Semua manusia dilahirkan bebas dan samarata dari segi kemuliaan dan hak-hak.</text>
              <doc_id>39</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Mereka mempunyai pemikiran dan perasaan hati dan hendaklah bertindak di antara satu sama lain dengan semangat persaudaraan.</text>
              <doc_id>40</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>(Malay) &#8226; Semua orang dilahirkan merdeka dan mempunyai martabat</text>
              <doc_id>41</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>dan hak-hak yang sama.</text>
              <doc_id>42</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Mereka dikaruniai akal dan hati nurani dan hendaknya bergaul satu sama lain dalam semangat persaudaraan.</text>
              <doc_id>43</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>(Indonesian) There is only 50% overlap at the word level, but the actual vocabulary overlap is much higher, e.g., there is only one word in the Malay text that does not exist in Indonesian: samarata (&#8216;equal&#8217;).</text>
              <doc_id>44</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Other differences are due to the use of different morphological forms, e.g., hendaklah vs. hendaknya (&#8216;conscience&#8217;), derivational variants of hendak (&#8216;want&#8217;).</text>
              <doc_id>45</doc_id>
              <sec_id>3</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Of course, word choice in translation is often a matter of taste.</text>
              <doc_id>46</doc_id>
              <sec_id>4</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Thus, we asked a native speaker of Indonesian to adapt the Malay version to Indonesian while preserving as many words as possible:</text>
              <doc_id>47</doc_id>
              <sec_id>5</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>dan hak-hak yang sama.</text>
              <doc_id>48</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Mereka mempunyai pemikiran dan perasaan dan hendaklah bergaul satu sama lain dalam semangat persaudaraan.</text>
              <doc_id>49</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>(Indonesian) 2 English: All human beings are born free and equal in dignity and rights.</text>
              <doc_id>50</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>They are endowed with reason and conscience and should act towards one another in a spirit of brotherhood.</text>
              <doc_id>51</doc_id>
              <sec_id>3</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Obtaining this latter version from the original Malay text requires three word-level operations: (1) deletion of dari, segi, (2) insertion of yang, sama, and (3) substitution of samarata with mempunyai.</text>
              <doc_id>52</doc_id>
              <sec_id>4</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Unfortunately, we do not have parallel Malay- Indonesian text, which complicates the process of learning when to apply these operations.</text>
              <doc_id>53</doc_id>
              <sec_id>5</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Thus, below we restrict our attention to the simplest and most common operation of word substitution only, leaving the other two 3 operations for future work.</text>
              <doc_id>54</doc_id>
              <sec_id>6</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Note that word substitution is enough in many cases, e.g., it is all that is needed for the following Malay-Indonesian sentence pair: 4</text>
              <doc_id>55</doc_id>
              <sec_id>7</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>&#8226; KDNK Malaysia dijangka cecah 8 peratus pada tahun 2010.</text>
              <doc_id>56</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>&#8226; PDB Malaysia akan mencapai 8 persen pada tahun 2010.</text>
              <doc_id>57</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
        </paragraphs>
        <subsections/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <index>4</index>
        <title>4 Method</title>
        <text>We improve machine translation from a resourcepoor language (Indonesian) to English by adapting a bi-text for a related resource-rich language (Malay) and English, using word-level and phrase-level paraphrases and cross-lingual morphological variants.</text>
        <paragraphs>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>We improve machine translation from a resourcepoor language (Indonesian) to English by adapting a bi-text for a related resource-rich language (Malay) and English, using word-level and phrase-level paraphrases and cross-lingual morphological variants.</text>
              <doc_id>58</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
        </paragraphs>
        <subsections>
          <subsection>
            <index>0</index>
            <title>4.1 Word-Level Paraphrasing</title>
            <text>Given a Malay sentence, we generate a confusion network containing multiple Indonesian word-level paraphrase options for each Malay word. Each such Indonesian option is associated with a corresponding weight in the network, which is defined as the probability of this option being a translation of the original Malay word (see Eq. 1 below). We decode this confusion network using a large Indonesian language model, thus generating a ranked list of n corresponding adapted &#8220;Indonesian&#8221; sentences. Then, we pair each such adapted &#8220;Indonesian&#8221; sentence with the English counter-part for the Malay sentence it was derived from, thus obtaining a synthetic &#8220;Indonesian&#8221;&#8211;English bi-text. Finally, we combine this synthetic bi-text with the original Indonesian&#8211;English one to train the final Indonesian&#8211;English SMT system. Below we first describe how we generate wordlevel Indonesian options and corresponding weights for the Malay words. Then, we explain how we build, decode, and improve the confusion network. 3 There are other potentially useful operations, e.g., a correct translation for the Malay samarata can be obtained by splitting it into the Indonesian sequence sama rata. 4 Malaysia&#8217;s GDP is expected to reach 8 percent in 2010. 288 4.1.1 Inducing Word-Level Paraphrases We use pivoting over English to induce potential Indonesian translations for a given Malay word. First, we generate separate word-level alignments for the Indonesian&#8211;English and the Malay&#8211;English bi-texts. Then, we induce Indonesian-Malay word translation pairs assuming that if an Indonesian word i and a Malay word m are aligned to the same English word e, they could be mutual translations. Each translation pair is associated with a conditional probability, estimated by pivoting over English:
likelihood from the word alignments. Following (Callison-Burch et al., 2006), we further assume that i is conditionally independent of m given e.
Given a Malay sentence, we construct an Indonesian confusion network, where each Malay word is augmented with a set of network transitions: possible Indonesian word translations. The weight of such a transition is the conditional Indonesian- Malay translation probability as calculated by Eq. 1; the original Malay word is assigned a weight of 1. Note that we paraphrase each word in the input Malay sentence as opposed to only those Malay words that we believe not to exist in Indonesian, e.g., because they do not appear in our Indonesian monolingual text. This is necessary because of the large number of false friends and partial cognates between Malay and Indonesian (see Section 3). Finally, we decode the confusion network for a Malay sentence using a large Indonesian language model, and we extract an n-best list. 5 Table 1 shows the 10-best adapted &#8220;Indonesian&#8221; sentences 6 we generated for the confusion network in Figure 1.
4.1.3 Further Refinements
Many of our paraphrases are bad: some have very low probabilities, while others involve rare words for which the probability estimates are unreliable. 5 For balance, in case of less than n adaptations for a Malay sentence, we randomly repeat some of the available ones. 6 According to a native Indonesian speaker, options 1 and 3 in Table 1 are perfect adaptations, options 2 and 5 have a wrong word order, and the rest are grammatical though not perfect. Moreover, the options we propose for a Malay word are inherently restricted to the small Indonesian vocabulary of the Indonesian&#8211;English bi-text. Below we describe how we address these issues. Score-based filtering. We filter out translation pairs whose probabilities (Eq. 1) are lower than some threshold (tuned on the dev dataset), e.g., 0.01. Improved estimations for Pr(i|e). We concatenate k copies of the Indonesian&#8211;English bi-text and one copy of the Malay&#8211;English bi-text, where the value of k is selected so that we have roughly the same number of Indonesian and Malay sentences. Then, we generate word-level alignments for the resulting bi-text. Finally, we truncate these alignments keeping them for one copy of the original Indonesian&#8211;English bi-text only. Thus, we end up with improved word alignments for the Indonesian&#8211; English bi-text, and with better estimations for Eq. 1. Since Malay and Indonesian share many cognates, this improves word alignments for Indonesian words that occur rarely in the small Indonesian&#8211;English bitext but are relatively frequent in the larger Malay&#8211; English one; it also helps for some frequent words. Cross-lingual morphological variants. We increase the Indonesian options for a Malay word using morphology. Since the set of Indonesian options for a Malay word in pivoting is restricted to the Indonesian vocabulary of the small Indonesian&#8211; English bi-text, this is a severe limitation of pivoting. Thus, assuming a large monolingual Indonesian text, we first build a lexicon of the words in the text. Then, we lemmatize these words using two different lemmatizers: the Malay lemmatizer of Baldwin and Awab (2006), and a similar Indonesian lemmatizer. Since these two analyzers have different strengths and weaknesses, we combine their outputs to increase recall. Next, we group all Indonesian words that share the same lemma, e.g., for minum, we obtain {diminum, diminumkan, diminumnya, makan-minum, makananminuman, meminum, meminumkan, meminumnya, meminumminuman, minum, minum-minum, minum-minuman, minuman, minumanku, minumannya, peminum, peminumnya, perminum, terminum}. Since Malay and Indonesian are subject to the same morphological processes and share many lemmata, we use such groups to propose Indonesian translation options for a Malay word. We first lemmatize the target Malay word, and then we find all groups of Indonesian words the Malay lemmata belong to.
The union of these groups is the set of morphological variants that we will add to the confusion network as additional options for the Malay word. 7 For example, given seperminuman (&#8216;drinking&#8217;) in the Malay input, we first find its stem minum, and then we get the above example set of Indonesian words, which contains some reasonable substitutes such as minuman (&#8216;drink&#8217;). In the confusion network, the weight of the original Malay word is set to 1, while the weight of a morphological option is one minus the minimum edit distance ratio (Ristad and Yianilos, 1998) between it and the Malay word, multiplied by the highest probability for all pivoting variants for the Malay word.</text>
            <paragraphs>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Given a Malay sentence, we generate a confusion network containing multiple Indonesian word-level paraphrase options for each Malay word.</text>
                  <doc_id>59</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Each such Indonesian option is associated with a corresponding weight in the network, which is defined as the probability of this option being a translation of the original Malay word (see Eq.</text>
                  <doc_id>60</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>1 below).</text>
                  <doc_id>61</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>2</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We decode this confusion network using a large Indonesian language model, thus generating a ranked list of n corresponding adapted &#8220;Indonesian&#8221; sentences.</text>
                  <doc_id>62</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>3</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Then, we pair each such adapted &#8220;Indonesian&#8221; sentence with the English counter-part for the Malay sentence it was derived from, thus obtaining a synthetic &#8220;Indonesian&#8221;&#8211;English bi-text.</text>
                  <doc_id>63</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>4</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Finally, we combine this synthetic bi-text with the original Indonesian&#8211;English one to train the final Indonesian&#8211;English SMT system.</text>
                  <doc_id>64</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>5</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Below we first describe how we generate wordlevel Indonesian options and corresponding weights for the Malay words.</text>
                  <doc_id>65</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>6</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Then, we explain how we build, decode, and improve the confusion network.</text>
                  <doc_id>66</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>7</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>3 There are other potentially useful operations, e.g., a correct translation for the Malay samarata can be obtained by splitting it into the Indonesian sequence sama rata.</text>
                  <doc_id>67</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>8</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>4 Malaysia&#8217;s GDP is expected to reach 8 percent in 2010.</text>
                  <doc_id>68</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>9</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>288 4.1.1 Inducing Word-Level Paraphrases We use pivoting over English to induce potential Indonesian translations for a given Malay word.</text>
                  <doc_id>69</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>10</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>First, we generate separate word-level alignments for the Indonesian&#8211;English and the Malay&#8211;English bi-texts.</text>
                  <doc_id>70</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>11</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Then, we induce Indonesian-Malay word translation pairs assuming that if an Indonesian word i and a Malay word m are aligned to the same English word e, they could be mutual translations.</text>
                  <doc_id>71</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>12</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Each translation pair is associated with a conditional probability, estimated by pivoting over English:</text>
                  <doc_id>72</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>13</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>likelihood from the word alignments.</text>
                  <doc_id>73</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Following (Callison-Burch et al., 2006), we further assume that i is conditionally independent of m given e.</text>
                  <doc_id>74</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Given a Malay sentence, we construct an Indonesian confusion network, where each Malay word is augmented with a set of network transitions: possible Indonesian word translations.</text>
                  <doc_id>75</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>The weight of such a transition is the conditional Indonesian- Malay translation probability as calculated by Eq.</text>
                  <doc_id>76</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>1; the original Malay word is assigned a weight of 1.</text>
                  <doc_id>77</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>2</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Note that we paraphrase each word in the input Malay sentence as opposed to only those Malay words that we believe not to exist in Indonesian, e.g., because they do not appear in our Indonesian monolingual text.</text>
                  <doc_id>78</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>3</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>This is necessary because of the large number of false friends and partial cognates between Malay and Indonesian (see Section 3).</text>
                  <doc_id>79</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>4</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Finally, we decode the confusion network for a Malay sentence using a large Indonesian language model, and we extract an n-best list.</text>
                  <doc_id>80</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>5</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>5 Table 1 shows the 10-best adapted &#8220;Indonesian&#8221; sentences 6 we generated for the confusion network in Figure 1.</text>
                  <doc_id>81</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>6</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>4.1.3 Further Refinements</text>
                  <doc_id>82</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Many of our paraphrases are bad: some have very low probabilities, while others involve rare words for which the probability estimates are unreliable.</text>
                  <doc_id>83</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>5 For balance, in case of less than n adaptations for a Malay sentence, we randomly repeat some of the available ones.</text>
                  <doc_id>84</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>6 According to a native Indonesian speaker, options 1 and 3 in Table 1 are perfect adaptations, options 2 and 5 have a wrong word order, and the rest are grammatical though not perfect.</text>
                  <doc_id>85</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>2</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Moreover, the options we propose for a Malay word are inherently restricted to the small Indonesian vocabulary of the Indonesian&#8211;English bi-text.</text>
                  <doc_id>86</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>3</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Below we describe how we address these issues.</text>
                  <doc_id>87</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>4</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Score-based filtering.</text>
                  <doc_id>88</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>5</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We filter out translation pairs whose probabilities (Eq.</text>
                  <doc_id>89</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>6</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>1) are lower than some threshold (tuned on the dev dataset), e.g., 0.01.</text>
                  <doc_id>90</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>7</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Improved estimations for Pr(i|e).</text>
                  <doc_id>91</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>8</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We concatenate k copies of the Indonesian&#8211;English bi-text and one copy of the Malay&#8211;English bi-text, where the value of k is selected so that we have roughly the same number of Indonesian and Malay sentences.</text>
                  <doc_id>92</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>9</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Then, we generate word-level alignments for the resulting bi-text.</text>
                  <doc_id>93</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>10</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Finally, we truncate these alignments keeping them for one copy of the original Indonesian&#8211;English bi-text only.</text>
                  <doc_id>94</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>11</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Thus, we end up with improved word alignments for the Indonesian&#8211; English bi-text, and with better estimations for Eq.</text>
                  <doc_id>95</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>12</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>1.</text>
                  <doc_id>96</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>13</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Since Malay and Indonesian share many cognates, this improves word alignments for Indonesian words that occur rarely in the small Indonesian&#8211;English bitext but are relatively frequent in the larger Malay&#8211; English one; it also helps for some frequent words.</text>
                  <doc_id>97</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>14</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Cross-lingual morphological variants.</text>
                  <doc_id>98</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>15</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We increase the Indonesian options for a Malay word using morphology.</text>
                  <doc_id>99</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>16</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Since the set of Indonesian options for a Malay word in pivoting is restricted to the Indonesian vocabulary of the small Indonesian&#8211; English bi-text, this is a severe limitation of pivoting.</text>
                  <doc_id>100</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>17</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Thus, assuming a large monolingual Indonesian text, we first build a lexicon of the words in the text.</text>
                  <doc_id>101</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>18</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Then, we lemmatize these words using two different lemmatizers: the Malay lemmatizer of Baldwin and Awab (2006), and a similar Indonesian lemmatizer.</text>
                  <doc_id>102</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>19</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Since these two analyzers have different strengths and weaknesses, we combine their outputs to increase recall.</text>
                  <doc_id>103</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>20</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Next, we group all Indonesian words that share the same lemma, e.g., for minum, we obtain {diminum, diminumkan, diminumnya, makan-minum, makananminuman, meminum, meminumkan, meminumnya, meminumminuman, minum, minum-minum, minum-minuman, minuman, minumanku, minumannya, peminum, peminumnya, perminum, terminum}.</text>
                  <doc_id>104</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>21</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Since Malay and Indonesian are subject to the same morphological processes and share many lemmata, we use such groups to propose Indonesian translation options for a Malay word.</text>
                  <doc_id>105</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>22</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We first lemmatize the target Malay word, and then we find all groups of Indonesian words the Malay lemmata belong to.</text>
                  <doc_id>106</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>23</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>The union of these groups is the set of morphological variants that we will add to the confusion network as additional options for the Malay word.</text>
                  <doc_id>107</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>7 For example, given seperminuman (&#8216;drinking&#8217;) in the Malay input, we first find its stem minum, and then we get the above example set of Indonesian words, which contains some reasonable substitutes such as minuman (&#8216;drink&#8217;).</text>
                  <doc_id>108</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>In the confusion network, the weight of the original Malay word is set to 1, while the weight of a morphological option is one minus the minimum edit distance ratio (Ristad and Yianilos, 1998) between it and the Malay word, multiplied by the highest probability for all pivoting variants for the Malay word.</text>
                  <doc_id>109</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>2</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
            </paragraphs>
          </subsection>
          <subsection>
            <index>1</index>
            <title>4.2 Phrase-Level Paraphrasing</title>
            <text>Word-level paraphrasing ignores context when generating Indonesian variants, relying on the Indonesian language model to make the right contextual choice. We also try to model context more directly by generating adaptation options at the phrase level. 7 While the different morphological forms typically have different meanings, e.g., minum (&#8216;drink&#8217;) vs. peminum (&#8216;drinker&#8217;), in some cases the forms could have the same translation in English, e.g., minum (&#8216;drink&#8217;, verb) vs. minuman (&#8216;drink&#8217;, noun). This is our motivation for trying morphological variants, even though they are almost exclusively derivational, and thus quite risky as translational variants; see also (Nakov and Ng, 2011). Phrase-level paraphrase induction. We use standard phrase-based SMT techniques to build separate phrase tables for the Indonesian&#8211;English and the Malay&#8211;English bi-texts, where we have four conditional probabilities: forward/reverse phrase translation probability, and forward/reverse lexicalized phrase translation probability. We pivot over English to generate Indonesian-Malay phrase pairs, whose probabilities are derived from the corresponding ones in the two phrase tables using Eq. 1. Cross-lingual morphological variants. While phrase-level paraphrasing models context better, it remains limited in the size of its Indonesian vocabulary by the small Indonesian&#8211;English bi-text, just like word-level paraphrasing was. We address this by transforming the sentences in the development and the test Indonesian&#8211;English bi-texts into confusion networks, where we add Malay morphological variants for the Indonesian words, weighting them as before. Note that we do not alter the training bi-text.</text>
            <paragraphs>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Word-level paraphrasing ignores context when generating Indonesian variants, relying on the Indonesian language model to make the right contextual choice.</text>
                  <doc_id>110</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We also try to model context more directly by generating adaptation options at the phrase level.</text>
                  <doc_id>111</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>7 While the different morphological forms typically have different meanings, e.g., minum (&#8216;drink&#8217;) vs. peminum (&#8216;drinker&#8217;), in some cases the forms could have the same translation in English, e.g., minum (&#8216;drink&#8217;, verb) vs. minuman (&#8216;drink&#8217;, noun).</text>
                  <doc_id>112</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>2</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>This is our motivation for trying morphological variants, even though they are almost exclusively derivational, and thus quite risky as translational variants; see also (Nakov and Ng, 2011).</text>
                  <doc_id>113</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>3</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Phrase-level paraphrase induction.</text>
                  <doc_id>114</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>4</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We use standard phrase-based SMT techniques to build separate phrase tables for the Indonesian&#8211;English and the Malay&#8211;English bi-texts, where we have four conditional probabilities: forward/reverse phrase translation probability, and forward/reverse lexicalized phrase translation probability.</text>
                  <doc_id>115</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>5</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We pivot over English to generate Indonesian-Malay phrase pairs, whose probabilities are derived from the corresponding ones in the two phrase tables using Eq.</text>
                  <doc_id>116</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>6</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>1.</text>
                  <doc_id>117</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>7</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Cross-lingual morphological variants.</text>
                  <doc_id>118</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>8</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>While phrase-level paraphrasing models context better, it remains limited in the size of its Indonesian vocabulary by the small Indonesian&#8211;English bi-text, just like word-level paraphrasing was.</text>
                  <doc_id>119</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>9</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We address this by transforming the sentences in the development and the test Indonesian&#8211;English bi-texts into confusion networks, where we add Malay morphological variants for the Indonesian words, weighting them as before.</text>
                  <doc_id>120</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>10</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Note that we do not alter the training bi-text.</text>
                  <doc_id>121</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>11</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
            </paragraphs>
          </subsection>
          <subsection>
            <index>2</index>
            <title>4.3 Combining Bi-texts</title>
            <text>Balanced concatenation with repetitions. However, the two bi-texts are not directly comparable and are clearly not equally good as a source of training data for an Indonesian-English SMT system. For one thing, the &#8220;Indonesian&#8221;&#8211;English bi-text is obtained from n-best lists, i.e., it has exactly n very similar variants for each Malay sentence. Moreover, the original Malay&#8211;English bi-text is much larger in size than the Indonesian&#8211;English one, and now it has been further expanded n times in order to become an &#8220;Indonesian&#8221;&#8211;English bi-text, which means that it will dominate the concatenation due to its size. In order to counter-balance this, we repeat the smaller Indonesian&#8211;English bi-text enough times so that we can make the number of sentences it contains roughly the same as for the &#8220;Indonesian&#8221;&#8211;English bi-text; then we concatenate the two bi-texts and we train an SMT system on the resulting bi-text. Sophisticated phrase table combination. Finally, we experiment with a method for combining phrase tables proposed in (Nakov and Ng, 2009; Nakov and Ng, 2012). The first phrase table is extracted from word alignments for the balanced concatenation with repetitions, which are then truncated so that they are kept for only one copy of the Indonesian&#8211;English bi-text. The second table is built from the simple concatenation. The two tables are then merged as follows: all phrase pairs from the first one are retained, and to them are added those phrase pairs from the second one that are not present in the first one. Each phrase pair retains its original scores, which are further augmented with 1&#8211;3 additional feature scores indicating its origin: the first/second/third feature is 1 if the pair came from the first/second/both table(s), and 0 otherwise. We experiment using all three, the first two, or the first feature only; we also try setting the features to 0.5 instead of 0. This makes the following six combinations (0, 00, 000, .5, .5.5, .5.5.5); on testing, we use the one that achieves the highest BLEU score on the development set. Other possibilities for combining the phrase tables include using alternative decoding paths (Birch et al., 2007), simple linear interpolation, and direct phrase table merging with extra features (Callison- Burch et al., 2006); they were previously found inferior to the last two approaches above (Nakov and Ng, 2009; Nakov and Ng, 2012).</text>
            <paragraphs>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Balanced concatenation with repetitions.</text>
                  <doc_id>122</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>However, the two bi-texts are not directly comparable and are clearly not equally good as a source of training data for an Indonesian-English SMT system.</text>
                  <doc_id>123</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>For one thing, the &#8220;Indonesian&#8221;&#8211;English bi-text is obtained from n-best lists, i.e., it has exactly n very similar variants for each Malay sentence.</text>
                  <doc_id>124</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>2</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Moreover, the original Malay&#8211;English bi-text is much larger in size than the Indonesian&#8211;English one, and now it has been further expanded n times in order to become an &#8220;Indonesian&#8221;&#8211;English bi-text, which means that it will dominate the concatenation due to its size.</text>
                  <doc_id>125</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>3</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>In order to counter-balance this, we repeat the smaller Indonesian&#8211;English bi-text enough times so that we can make the number of sentences it contains roughly the same as for the &#8220;Indonesian&#8221;&#8211;English bi-text; then we concatenate the two bi-texts and we train an SMT system on the resulting bi-text.</text>
                  <doc_id>126</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>4</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Sophisticated phrase table combination.</text>
                  <doc_id>127</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>5</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Finally, we experiment with a method for combining phrase tables proposed in (Nakov and Ng, 2009; Nakov and Ng, 2012).</text>
                  <doc_id>128</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>6</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>The first phrase table is extracted from word alignments for the balanced concatenation with repetitions, which are then truncated so that they are kept for only one copy of the Indonesian&#8211;English bi-text.</text>
                  <doc_id>129</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>7</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>The second table is built from the simple concatenation.</text>
                  <doc_id>130</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>8</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>The two tables are then merged as follows: all phrase pairs from the first one are retained, and to them are added those phrase pairs from the second one that are not present in the first one.</text>
                  <doc_id>131</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>9</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Each phrase pair retains its original scores, which are further augmented with 1&#8211;3 additional feature scores indicating its origin: the first/second/third feature is 1 if the pair came from the first/second/both table(s), and 0 otherwise.</text>
                  <doc_id>132</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>10</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We experiment using all three, the first two, or the first feature only; we also try setting the features to 0.5 instead of 0.</text>
                  <doc_id>133</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>11</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>This makes the following six combinations (0, 00, 000, .5, .5.5, .5.5.5); on testing, we use the one that achieves the highest BLEU score on the development set.</text>
                  <doc_id>134</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>12</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Other possibilities for combining the phrase tables include using alternative decoding paths (Birch et al., 2007), simple linear interpolation, and direct phrase table merging with extra features (Callison- Burch et al., 2006); they were previously found inferior to the last two approaches above (Nakov and Ng, 2009; Nakov and Ng, 2012).</text>
                  <doc_id>135</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>13</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
            </paragraphs>
          </subsection>
        </subsections>
      </section>
      <section>
        <index>5</index>
        <title>5 Experiments</title>
        <text>We run two kinds of experiments: (a) isolated, where we train on the synthetic &#8220;Indonesian&#8221;&#8211; English bi-text only, and (b) combined, where we combine it with the Indonesian&#8211;English bi-text.</text>
        <paragraphs>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>We run two kinds of experiments: (a) isolated, where we train on the synthetic &#8220;Indonesian&#8221;&#8211; English bi-text only, and (b) combined, where we combine it with the Indonesian&#8211;English bi-text.</text>
              <doc_id>136</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
        </paragraphs>
        <subsections>
          <subsection>
            <index>0</index>
            <title>5.1 Datasets</title>
            <text>&#8226; Indonesian&#8211;English train bi-text (IN2EN): 28,383 sentence pairs; 915,192 English tokens; 796,787 Indonesian tokens; &#8226; Indon.&#8211;English dev bi-text (IN2EN-dev): 2,000 sentence pairs; 36,584 English tokens; 35,708 Indonesian tokens; &#8226; Indon.&#8211;English test bi-text (IN2EN-test): 2,018 sentence pairs; 37,101 English tokens; 35,509 Indonesian tokens; &#8226; Monolingual English text (EN-LM): 174,443 sentences; 5,071,988 English tokens.
We also use a Malay&#8211;English set (to be turned into &#8220;Indonesian&#8221;&#8211;English), and monolingual Indonesian text (for decoding the confusion network):
&#8226; Malay&#8211;English train bi-text (ML2EN): 290,000 sentence pairs; 8,638,780 English tokens; 8,061,729 Malay tokens; &#8226; Monolingual Indonesian text (IN-LM): 1,132,082 sentences; 20,452,064 Indonesian tokens.</text>
            <paragraphs>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>&#8226; Indonesian&#8211;English train bi-text (IN2EN): 28,383 sentence pairs; 915,192 English tokens; 796,787 Indonesian tokens; &#8226; Indon.&#8211;English dev bi-text (IN2EN-dev): 2,000 sentence pairs; 36,584 English tokens; 35,708 Indonesian tokens; &#8226; Indon.&#8211;English test bi-text (IN2EN-test): 2,018 sentence pairs; 37,101 English tokens; 35,509 Indonesian tokens; &#8226; Monolingual English text (EN-LM): 174,443 sentences; 5,071,988 English tokens.</text>
                  <doc_id>137</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We also use a Malay&#8211;English set (to be turned into &#8220;Indonesian&#8221;&#8211;English), and monolingual Indonesian text (for decoding the confusion network):</text>
                  <doc_id>138</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>&#8226; Malay&#8211;English train bi-text (ML2EN): 290,000 sentence pairs; 8,638,780 English tokens; 8,061,729 Malay tokens; &#8226; Monolingual Indonesian text (IN-LM): 1,132,082 sentences; 20,452,064 Indonesian tokens.</text>
                  <doc_id>139</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
            </paragraphs>
          </subsection>
          <subsection>
            <index>1</index>
            <title>5.2 Baseline Systems</title>
            <text>We build five baseline systems &#8211; two using a single bi-text, ML2EN or IN2EN, and three combining ML2EN and IN2EN, using simple concatenation, balanced concatenation, and sophisticated phrase table combination. The last combination is a very strong baseline and the most relevant one we need to improve upon.</text>
            <paragraphs>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We build five baseline systems &#8211; two using a single bi-text, ML2EN or IN2EN, and three combining ML2EN and IN2EN, using simple concatenation, balanced concatenation, and sophisticated phrase table combination.</text>
                  <doc_id>140</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>The last combination is a very strong baseline and the most relevant one we need to improve upon.</text>
                  <doc_id>141</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
            </paragraphs>
          </subsection>
          <subsection>
            <index>2</index>
            <title>5.3 Isolated Experiments</title>
            <text>The isolated experiments only use the adapted &#8220;Indonesian&#8221;&#8211;English bi-text, which allows for a direct comparison to using ML2EN / IN2EN only.
5.3.1 Word-Level Paraphrasing In our word-level paraphrasing experiments, we adapt Malay to Indonesian using three kinds of confusion networks (see Section 4.1.3 for details):
&#8226; CN:pivot &#8211; using word-level pivoting only; &#8226; CN:pivot &#8242; &#8211; using word-level pivoting, with probabilities from word alignments for IN2EN that were improved using ML2EN; &#8226; CN:pivot &#8242; +morph &#8211; CN:pivot &#8242; augmented with cross-lingual morphological variants.
There are two parameter values to be tuned on IN2EN-dev for the above confusion networks: (1) the minimum pivoting probability threshold for the Malay-Indonesian word-level paraphrases, and (2) the number of n-best Indonesian-adapted sentences that are to be generated for each input Malay sentence. We try {0.001, 0.005, 0.01, 0.05} for the threshold and {1, 5, 10} for n.
5.3.2 Phrase-Level Paraphrasing
In our phrase-level paraphrasing experiments, we use pivoted phrase tables (PPT) with the following features for each phrase table entry (in addition to the phrase penalty; see Section 4.2 for more details):
&#8226; PPT:1 &#8211; only uses the forward conditional translation probability; &#8226; PPT:4 &#8211; uses all four conditional probabilities; &#8226; PPT:4::CN:morph &#8211; PPT:4 but used with a cross-lingual morphological confusion network for the dev/test Indonesian sentences.
Here we tune one parameter only: the number of n-best Indonesian-adapted sentences to be generated for each input Malay sentence; we try {1, 5, 10}.</text>
            <paragraphs>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>The isolated experiments only use the adapted &#8220;Indonesian&#8221;&#8211;English bi-text, which allows for a direct comparison to using ML2EN / IN2EN only.</text>
                  <doc_id>142</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>5.3.1 Word-Level Paraphrasing In our word-level paraphrasing experiments, we adapt Malay to Indonesian using three kinds of confusion networks (see Section 4.1.3 for details):</text>
                  <doc_id>143</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>&#8226; CN:pivot &#8211; using word-level pivoting only; &#8226; CN:pivot &#8242; &#8211; using word-level pivoting, with probabilities from word alignments for IN2EN that were improved using ML2EN; &#8226; CN:pivot &#8242; +morph &#8211; CN:pivot &#8242; augmented with cross-lingual morphological variants.</text>
                  <doc_id>144</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>There are two parameter values to be tuned on IN2EN-dev for the above confusion networks: (1) the minimum pivoting probability threshold for the Malay-Indonesian word-level paraphrases, and (2) the number of n-best Indonesian-adapted sentences that are to be generated for each input Malay sentence.</text>
                  <doc_id>145</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We try {0.001, 0.005, 0.01, 0.05} for the threshold and {1, 5, 10} for n.</text>
                  <doc_id>146</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>5.3.2 Phrase-Level Paraphrasing</text>
                  <doc_id>147</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>In our phrase-level paraphrasing experiments, we use pivoted phrase tables (PPT) with the following features for each phrase table entry (in addition to the phrase penalty; see Section 4.2 for more details):</text>
                  <doc_id>148</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>&#8226; PPT:1 &#8211; only uses the forward conditional translation probability; &#8226; PPT:4 &#8211; uses all four conditional probabilities; &#8226; PPT:4::CN:morph &#8211; PPT:4 but used with a cross-lingual morphological confusion network for the dev/test Indonesian sentences.</text>
                  <doc_id>149</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Here we tune one parameter only: the number of n-best Indonesian-adapted sentences to be generated for each input Malay sentence; we try {1, 5, 10}.</text>
                  <doc_id>150</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
            </paragraphs>
          </subsection>
          <subsection>
            <index>3</index>
            <title>5.4 Combined Experiments</title>
            <text>These experiments assess the impact of our adaptation approach when combined with the original Indonesian&#8211;English bi-text IN2EN as opposed to combining ML2EN with IN2EN (as was in the last three baselines). We experiment with the same three combinations: simple concatenation, balanced concatenation, and sophisticated phrase table combination. We tune the parameters as before; for the last combination, we further tune the six extra feature combinations (see Section 4.3 for details).</text>
            <paragraphs>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>These experiments assess the impact of our adaptation approach when combined with the original Indonesian&#8211;English bi-text IN2EN as opposed to combining ML2EN with IN2EN (as was in the last three baselines).</text>
                  <doc_id>151</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We experiment with the same three combinations: simple concatenation, balanced concatenation, and sophisticated phrase table combination.</text>
                  <doc_id>152</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We tune the parameters as before; for the last combination, we further tune the six extra feature combinations (see Section 4.3 for details).</text>
                  <doc_id>153</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>2</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
            </paragraphs>
          </subsection>
        </subsections>
      </section>
      <section>
        <index>6</index>
        <title>6 Results and Discussion</title>
        <text>For all tables, statistically significant improvements (p &lt; 0.01), according to Collins et al. (2005)&#8217;s sign test, over the baseline are in bold; in case of two baselines, underline is used for the second baseline.</text>
        <paragraphs>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>For all tables, statistically significant improvements (p &lt; 0.01), according to Collins et al. (2005)&#8217;s sign test, over the baseline are in bold; in case of two baselines, underline is used for the second baseline.</text>
              <doc_id>154</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
        </paragraphs>
        <subsections>
          <subsection>
            <index>0</index>
            <title>6.1 Baseline Experiments</title>
            <text>The results for the baseline systems are shown in Table 2. We can see that training on ML2EN instead of IN2EN yields over 4 points absolute drop in BLEU (Papineni et al., 2002) score, even though ML2EN is about 10 times larger than IN2EN and both bi-texts are from the same domain. This confirms the existence of important differences between Malay and Indonesian. While simple concatenation does not help, balanced concatenation with repetitions improves by 1.12 BLEU points over IN2EN, which shows the importance of giving IN2EN a proper weight in the combined bi-text. This is further reconfirmed by the sophisticated phrase table combination, which yields an additional absolute gain of 0.31 BLEU points.</text>
            <paragraphs>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>The results for the baseline systems are shown in Table 2.</text>
                  <doc_id>155</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We can see that training on ML2EN instead of IN2EN yields over 4 points absolute drop in BLEU (Papineni et al., 2002) score, even though ML2EN is about 10 times larger than IN2EN and both bi-texts are from the same domain.</text>
                  <doc_id>156</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>This confirms the existence of important differences between Malay and Indonesian.</text>
                  <doc_id>157</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>2</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>While simple concatenation does not help, balanced concatenation with repetitions improves by 1.12 BLEU points over IN2EN, which shows the importance of giving IN2EN a proper weight in the combined bi-text.</text>
                  <doc_id>158</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>3</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>This is further reconfirmed by the sophisticated phrase table combination, which yields an additional absolute gain of 0.31 BLEU points.</text>
                  <doc_id>159</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>4</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
            </paragraphs>
          </subsection>
          <subsection>
            <index>1</index>
            <title>6.2 Isolated Experiments</title>
            <text>Table 3 shows the results for the isolated experiments. We can see that word-level paraphrasing improves by up to 5.56 and 1.39 BLEU points over the two baselines (both statistically significant). Compared to ML2EN, CN:pivot yields an absolute improvement of 4.41 BLEU points, CN:pivot &#8242; adds another 0.59, and CN:pivot &#8242; +morph adds 0.56 more. The scores for TER (v. 0.7.25) and METEOR (v. 1.3) are on par with those for BLEU (NIST v. 13).
Table 3 further shows that the optimal parameters for the word-level SMT systems (CN:*) involve a very low probability cutoff, and a high number of n-best sentences. This shows that they are robust to noise, probably because bad source-side phrases are unlikely to match the test-time input. Note also the effect of repetitions: good word choices are shared by many n-best sentences, and thus they would have higher probabilities compared to bad word choices.
+ CN:pivot 19.99 (+1.50) (0.001,1best) 20.16 (+0.37) (0.001,10best) 20.32 (+0.22) (0.01,10best,.5.5)
+ CN:pivot &#8242; 20.03 (+1.54) (0.05,1best) 20.80 (+1.01) (0.05,10best) 20.55 (+0.45) (0.05,10best,.5.5)
(ii) + CN:pivot &#8242; +morph 20.60 (+2.11) (0.01,10best) 21.15 (+1.36) (0.01,10best) 21.05 (+0.95) (0.01,5best,00)
+ PPT:1 20.61 (+2.12) (1best) 20.71 (+0.92) (10best) 20.32 (+0.22) (1best,000)
+ PPT:4 20.75 (+2.26) (1best) 21.08 (+1.29) (5best) 20.76 (+0.66) (10best,.5.5.5)
The gap between ML2EN and IN2EN for unigram precision could be explained by vocabulary differences between Malay and Indonesian. Compared to IN2EN, all CN:* models have higher 2/3/4-gram precision. However, CN:pivot has lower unigram precision, which could be due to bad word alignments, as the results for CN:pivot &#8242; show.
When morphological variants are further added, the unigram precision improves by almost 1% absolute over CN:pivot &#8242; . This shows the importance of morphology for overcoming the limitations of the small Indonesian vocabulary of the IN2EN bi-text.
The lower part of Table 3 shows that phrase-level paraphrasing performs a bit better. This confirms the importance of modeling context for closely-related languages like Malay and Indonesian, which are rich in false friends and partial cognates. We further see that using more scores in the phrase table is better. Extending the Indonesian vocabulary with cross-lingual morphological variants is still helpful, though not as much as at the word-level.
Finally, the combination of the output of the best PPT and the best CN systems using MEMT (Heafield and Lavie, 2010) yields even further improvements, which shows that the two kinds of paraphrases are complementary. The best overall BLEU score for our isolated experiments is 21.24, which is better than the results for all five baselines in Table 2, including the three bi-text combination baselines, which only achieve up to 20.10 BLEU.</text>
            <paragraphs>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Table 3 shows the results for the isolated experiments.</text>
                  <doc_id>160</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We can see that word-level paraphrasing improves by up to 5.56 and 1.39 BLEU points over the two baselines (both statistically significant).</text>
                  <doc_id>161</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Compared to ML2EN, CN:pivot yields an absolute improvement of 4.41 BLEU points, CN:pivot &#8242; adds another 0.59, and CN:pivot &#8242; +morph adds 0.56 more.</text>
                  <doc_id>162</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>2</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>The scores for TER (v.</text>
                  <doc_id>163</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>3</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>0.7.25) and METEOR (v.</text>
                  <doc_id>164</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>4</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>1.3) are on par with those for BLEU (NIST v.</text>
                  <doc_id>165</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>5</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>13).</text>
                  <doc_id>166</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>6</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Table 3 further shows that the optimal parameters for the word-level SMT systems (CN:*) involve a very low probability cutoff, and a high number of n-best sentences.</text>
                  <doc_id>167</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>This shows that they are robust to noise, probably because bad source-side phrases are unlikely to match the test-time input.</text>
                  <doc_id>168</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Note also the effect of repetitions: good word choices are shared by many n-best sentences, and thus they would have higher probabilities compared to bad word choices.</text>
                  <doc_id>169</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>2</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>+ CN:pivot 19.99 (+1.50) (0.001,1best) 20.16 (+0.37) (0.001,10best) 20.32 (+0.22) (0.01,10best,.5.5)</text>
                  <doc_id>170</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>+ CN:pivot &#8242; 20.03 (+1.54) (0.05,1best) 20.80 (+1.01) (0.05,10best) 20.55 (+0.45) (0.05,10best,.5.5)</text>
                  <doc_id>171</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>(ii) + CN:pivot &#8242; +morph 20.60 (+2.11) (0.01,10best) 21.15 (+1.36) (0.01,10best) 21.05 (+0.95) (0.01,5best,00)</text>
                  <doc_id>172</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>+ PPT:1 20.61 (+2.12) (1best) 20.71 (+0.92) (10best) 20.32 (+0.22) (1best,000)</text>
                  <doc_id>173</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>+ PPT:4 20.75 (+2.26) (1best) 21.08 (+1.29) (5best) 20.76 (+0.66) (10best,.5.5.5)</text>
                  <doc_id>174</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>The gap between ML2EN and IN2EN for unigram precision could be explained by vocabulary differences between Malay and Indonesian.</text>
                  <doc_id>175</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Compared to IN2EN, all CN:* models have higher 2/3/4-gram precision.</text>
                  <doc_id>176</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>However, CN:pivot has lower unigram precision, which could be due to bad word alignments, as the results for CN:pivot &#8242; show.</text>
                  <doc_id>177</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>2</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>When morphological variants are further added, the unigram precision improves by almost 1% absolute over CN:pivot &#8242; .</text>
                  <doc_id>178</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>This shows the importance of morphology for overcoming the limitations of the small Indonesian vocabulary of the IN2EN bi-text.</text>
                  <doc_id>179</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>The lower part of Table 3 shows that phrase-level paraphrasing performs a bit better.</text>
                  <doc_id>180</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>This confirms the importance of modeling context for closely-related languages like Malay and Indonesian, which are rich in false friends and partial cognates.</text>
                  <doc_id>181</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We further see that using more scores in the phrase table is better.</text>
                  <doc_id>182</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>2</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Extending the Indonesian vocabulary with cross-lingual morphological variants is still helpful, though not as much as at the word-level.</text>
                  <doc_id>183</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>3</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Finally, the combination of the output of the best PPT and the best CN systems using MEMT (Heafield and Lavie, 2010) yields even further improvements, which shows that the two kinds of paraphrases are complementary.</text>
                  <doc_id>184</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>The best overall BLEU score for our isolated experiments is 21.24, which is better than the results for all five baselines in Table 2, including the three bi-text combination baselines, which only achieve up to 20.10 BLEU.</text>
                  <doc_id>185</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
            </paragraphs>
          </subsection>
          <subsection>
            <index>2</index>
            <title>6.3 Combined Experiments</title>
            <text>Table 4 shows the performance of the three bitext combination strategies (see Section 4.3 for additional details) when applied to combine IN2EN (1) with the original ML2EN and (2) with various adapted versions of it. We can see that for the word-level paraphrasing experiments (CN:*), all combinations except for CN:pivot perform significantly better than their corresponding baselines, but the improvements are most sizeable for the simple concatenation.
Note that while there is a difference of 0.31 BLEU points between the balanced concatenation and the sophisticated combination for the original ML2EN, they differ little for the adapted versions. This is probably due to the sophisticated combination assuming that the second bi-text is worse than the first one, which is not really the case for the adapted versions: as Table 3 shows, they all outperform IN2EN.
Overall, phrase-level paraphrasing performs a bit better than word-level paraphrasing, and system combination with MEMT improves even further. This is consistent with the isolated experiments.</text>
            <paragraphs>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Table 4 shows the performance of the three bitext combination strategies (see Section 4.3 for additional details) when applied to combine IN2EN (1) with the original ML2EN and (2) with various adapted versions of it.</text>
                  <doc_id>186</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>We can see that for the word-level paraphrasing experiments (CN:*), all combinations except for CN:pivot perform significantly better than their corresponding baselines, but the improvements are most sizeable for the simple concatenation.</text>
                  <doc_id>187</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Note that while there is a difference of 0.31 BLEU points between the balanced concatenation and the sophisticated combination for the original ML2EN, they differ little for the adapted versions.</text>
                  <doc_id>188</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>This is probably due to the sophisticated combination assuming that the second bi-text is worse than the first one, which is not really the case for the adapted versions: as Table 3 shows, they all outperform IN2EN.</text>
                  <doc_id>189</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph>
                <sentence>
                  <text>Overall, phrase-level paraphrasing performs a bit better than word-level paraphrasing, and system combination with MEMT improves even further.</text>
                  <doc_id>190</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>0</sec_id>
                </sentence>
                <sentence>
                  <text>This is consistent with the isolated experiments.</text>
                  <doc_id>191</doc_id>
                  <sec_id>1</sec_id>
                </sentence>
              </paragraph>
            </paragraphs>
          </subsection>
        </subsections>
      </section>
      <section>
        <index>7</index>
        <title>7 Further Analysis</title>
        <text>Paraphrasing non-Indonesian words only. In CN:* above, we paraphrased each word in the Malay input, because of false friends like polisi and partial cognates like nanti. This risks proposing worse alternatives, e.g., changing beliau (&#8216;he&#8217;, respectful) to ia (&#8216;he&#8217;, casual), which confusion network weights and LM would not always handle. Thus, we tried paraphrasing non-Indonesian words only, i.e., those not in IN-LM. Since IN-LM occasionally contains some Malay-specific words, we also tried paraphrasing words that occur at most t times in IN-LM. Table 5 shows that this hurts by up to 1 BLEU point for t = 0; 10, and a bit less for t = 20; 40.
System CN:pivot, t = 0 CN:pivot, t = 10 CN:pivot, t = 20 CN:pivot, t = 40 CN:pivot (i.e., paraphrase all)
BLEU 17.88 (0.01,5best) 17.88 (0.05,10best) 18.14 (0.01,5best) 18.34 (0.01,5best) 18.91 (0.005,10best)
Manual evaluation. We asked a native Indonesian speaker who does not speak Malay to judge whether our &#8220;Indonesian&#8221; adaptations are more understandable to him than the original Malay input for 100 random sentences. We presented him with two extreme systems: (a) the conservative CN:pivot,t=0 vs. (b) CN:pivot &#8242; +morph. Since the latter is noisy, the top 3 choices were judged for it. Table 6 shows that CN:pivot,t=0 is better/equal to the original 53%/31% of the time. In contrast, CN:pivot &#8242; +morph is typically worse than the original; even compared to the best in top 3, the better:worse ratio is 45%:43%.
Still, this latter model works better, which means that phrase-based SMT systems are robust to noise and prefer more variety. Note also that the judgments were at the sentence level, while phrases are sub-sentential, i.e., there can be many good phrases in a &#8220;bad&#8221; sentence.
Reversed Adaptation. In all experiments above, we were adapting the Malay sentences to look like Indonesian. Here we try to reverse the direction of adaptation, i.e., to adapt Indonesian to Malay: we thus build a &#8220;Malay&#8221; confusion network for each dev/test Indonesian sentence to be used as an input to a Malay&#8211;English SMT system trained on the ML2EN dataset. We tried two variations of this idea:
&#8226; lattice: Use Indonesian-to-Malay confusion networks directly as input to the ML2EN SMT system, i.e., tune a log-linear model using confusion networks for the source side of the IN2EN-dev dataset, and then evaluate the tuned system using confusion networks for the source side of the IN2EN-test dataset. &#8226; 1-best: Use the 1-best output from the Indonesian-to-Malay confusion network for each sentence of IN2EN-dev and IN2EN-test. Then pair each 1-best output with the corresponding English sentence. Finally, get an adapted &#8220;Malay&#8221;&#8211;English development set and an adapted &#8220;Malay&#8221;&#8211;English test set, and use them to tune and evaluate the ML2EN SMT system.
Table 7 shows that both variations perform worse than CN:pivot. We believe this is because lattice encodes many options, but does not use a Malay LM, while 1-best uses a Malay LM, but has to commit to 1-best. In contrast, CN:pivot uses both n-best outputs and an Indonesian LM; designing a similar setup for reversed adaptation is a research direction we would like to pursue in future work.
Adapting Macedonian to Bulgarian. We experimented with another pair of closely-related languages, 8 Macedonian (MK) and Bulgarian (BG), using data from a different, non-newswire domain: the OPUS corpus of movie subtitles (Tiedemann, 2009). We used datasets of sizes that are comparable to those in the previous experiments: 160K MK2EN and 1.5M BG2EN sentence pairs (1.2M and 11.5M EN words). Since the sentences were short, we used 10K MK2EN sentence pairs for tuning and testing (77K and 72K English words). For the LM, we used 9.2M Macedonian and 433M English words.
Table 8 shows that both CN:* and PPT:* yield statistically significant improvements over balanced concatenation with unadapted BG2EN; system combination with MEMT improves even further. This indicates that our approach can work for other pairs of related languages and even for other domains. We should note though that the improvements here are less sizeable than for Indonesian/Malay. This may be due to our monolingual MK dataset being smaller (10M MK vs. 20M IN words), and too noisy, containing many OCR errors, typos, concatenated words, and even some Bulgarian text. Moreover, Macedonian and Bulgarian are arguably somewhat more dissimilar than Malay and Indonesian.
8 There is a heated political and linguistic debate about
whether Macedonian represents a separate language or is a regional literary form of Bulgarian. Since there are no clear criteria for distinguishing a dialect from a language, linguists are divided on this issue. Politically, the Macedonian remains unrecognized as a language by Bulgaria and Greece.</text>
        <paragraphs>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>Paraphrasing non-Indonesian words only.</text>
              <doc_id>192</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>In CN:* above, we paraphrased each word in the Malay input, because of false friends like polisi and partial cognates like nanti.</text>
              <doc_id>193</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>This risks proposing worse alternatives, e.g., changing beliau (&#8216;he&#8217;, respectful) to ia (&#8216;he&#8217;, casual), which confusion network weights and LM would not always handle.</text>
              <doc_id>194</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Thus, we tried paraphrasing non-Indonesian words only, i.e., those not in IN-LM.</text>
              <doc_id>195</doc_id>
              <sec_id>3</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Since IN-LM occasionally contains some Malay-specific words, we also tried paraphrasing words that occur at most t times in IN-LM.</text>
              <doc_id>196</doc_id>
              <sec_id>4</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Table 5 shows that this hurts by up to 1 BLEU point for t = 0; 10, and a bit less for t = 20; 40.</text>
              <doc_id>197</doc_id>
              <sec_id>5</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>System CN:pivot, t = 0 CN:pivot, t = 10 CN:pivot, t = 20 CN:pivot, t = 40 CN:pivot (i.e., paraphrase all)</text>
              <doc_id>198</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>BLEU 17.88 (0.01,5best) 17.88 (0.05,10best) 18.14 (0.01,5best) 18.34 (0.01,5best) 18.91 (0.005,10best)</text>
              <doc_id>199</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>Manual evaluation.</text>
              <doc_id>200</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>We asked a native Indonesian speaker who does not speak Malay to judge whether our &#8220;Indonesian&#8221; adaptations are more understandable to him than the original Malay input for 100 random sentences.</text>
              <doc_id>201</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>We presented him with two extreme systems: (a) the conservative CN:pivot,t=0 vs. (b) CN:pivot &#8242; +morph.</text>
              <doc_id>202</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Since the latter is noisy, the top 3 choices were judged for it.</text>
              <doc_id>203</doc_id>
              <sec_id>3</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Table 6 shows that CN:pivot,t=0 is better/equal to the original 53%/31% of the time.</text>
              <doc_id>204</doc_id>
              <sec_id>4</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>In contrast, CN:pivot &#8242; +morph is typically worse than the original; even compared to the best in top 3, the better:worse ratio is 45%:43%.</text>
              <doc_id>205</doc_id>
              <sec_id>5</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>Still, this latter model works better, which means that phrase-based SMT systems are robust to noise and prefer more variety.</text>
              <doc_id>206</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Note also that the judgments were at the sentence level, while phrases are sub-sentential, i.e., there can be many good phrases in a &#8220;bad&#8221; sentence.</text>
              <doc_id>207</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>Reversed Adaptation.</text>
              <doc_id>208</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>In all experiments above, we were adapting the Malay sentences to look like Indonesian.</text>
              <doc_id>209</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Here we try to reverse the direction of adaptation, i.e., to adapt Indonesian to Malay: we thus build a &#8220;Malay&#8221; confusion network for each dev/test Indonesian sentence to be used as an input to a Malay&#8211;English SMT system trained on the ML2EN dataset.</text>
              <doc_id>210</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>We tried two variations of this idea:</text>
              <doc_id>211</doc_id>
              <sec_id>3</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>&#8226; lattice: Use Indonesian-to-Malay confusion networks directly as input to the ML2EN SMT system, i.e., tune a log-linear model using confusion networks for the source side of the IN2EN-dev dataset, and then evaluate the tuned system using confusion networks for the source side of the IN2EN-test dataset.</text>
              <doc_id>212</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>&#8226; 1-best: Use the 1-best output from the Indonesian-to-Malay confusion network for each sentence of IN2EN-dev and IN2EN-test.</text>
              <doc_id>213</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Then pair each 1-best output with the corresponding English sentence.</text>
              <doc_id>214</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Finally, get an adapted &#8220;Malay&#8221;&#8211;English development set and an adapted &#8220;Malay&#8221;&#8211;English test set, and use them to tune and evaluate the ML2EN SMT system.</text>
              <doc_id>215</doc_id>
              <sec_id>3</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>Table 7 shows that both variations perform worse than CN:pivot.</text>
              <doc_id>216</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>We believe this is because lattice encodes many options, but does not use a Malay LM, while 1-best uses a Malay LM, but has to commit to 1-best.</text>
              <doc_id>217</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>In contrast, CN:pivot uses both n-best outputs and an Indonesian LM; designing a similar setup for reversed adaptation is a research direction we would like to pursue in future work.</text>
              <doc_id>218</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>Adapting Macedonian to Bulgarian.</text>
              <doc_id>219</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>We experimented with another pair of closely-related languages, 8 Macedonian (MK) and Bulgarian (BG), using data from a different, non-newswire domain: the OPUS corpus of movie subtitles (Tiedemann, 2009).</text>
              <doc_id>220</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>We used datasets of sizes that are comparable to those in the previous experiments: 160K MK2EN and 1.5M BG2EN sentence pairs (1.2M and 11.5M EN words).</text>
              <doc_id>221</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Since the sentences were short, we used 10K MK2EN sentence pairs for tuning and testing (77K and 72K English words).</text>
              <doc_id>222</doc_id>
              <sec_id>3</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>For the LM, we used 9.2M Macedonian and 433M English words.</text>
              <doc_id>223</doc_id>
              <sec_id>4</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>Table 8 shows that both CN:* and PPT:* yield statistically significant improvements over balanced concatenation with unadapted BG2EN; system combination with MEMT improves even further.</text>
              <doc_id>224</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>This indicates that our approach can work for other pairs of related languages and even for other domains.</text>
              <doc_id>225</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>We should note though that the improvements here are less sizeable than for Indonesian/Malay.</text>
              <doc_id>226</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>This may be due to our monolingual MK dataset being smaller (10M MK vs. 20M IN words), and too noisy, containing many OCR errors, typos, concatenated words, and even some Bulgarian text.</text>
              <doc_id>227</doc_id>
              <sec_id>3</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Moreover, Macedonian and Bulgarian are arguably somewhat more dissimilar than Malay and Indonesian.</text>
              <doc_id>228</doc_id>
              <sec_id>4</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>8 There is a heated political and linguistic debate about</text>
              <doc_id>229</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>whether Macedonian represents a separate language or is a regional literary form of Bulgarian.</text>
              <doc_id>230</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Since there are no clear criteria for distinguishing a dialect from a language, linguists are divided on this issue.</text>
              <doc_id>231</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Politically, the Macedonian remains unrecognized as a language by Bulgaria and Greece.</text>
              <doc_id>232</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
        </paragraphs>
        <subsections/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <index>8</index>
        <title>8 Conclusion and Future Work</title>
        <text>We have presented a novel approach for improving machine translation for a resource-poor language by adapting a bi-text for a related resource-rich language, using confusion networks, word/phrase-level paraphrasing, and morphological analysis. We have achieved very significant improvements over several baselines (6.7 BLEU points over an unadapted version of ML2EN, 2.6 BLEU points over IN2EN, and 1.5&#8211;3 BLEU points over three bi-text combinations of ML2EN and IN2EN), thus proving the potential of the idea. We have further demonstrated the applicability of the general approach to other languages and domains. In future work, we would like to add word deletion, insertion, splitting, and concatenation as allowed editing operations. We further want to explore tighter integration of word-based and phrasebased paraphrasing. Finally, we plan experiments with other language pairs and application to other linguistic problems.</text>
        <paragraphs>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>We have presented a novel approach for improving machine translation for a resource-poor language by adapting a bi-text for a related resource-rich language, using confusion networks, word/phrase-level paraphrasing, and morphological analysis.</text>
              <doc_id>233</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>We have achieved very significant improvements over several baselines (6.7 BLEU points over an unadapted version of ML2EN, 2.6 BLEU points over IN2EN, and 1.5&#8211;3 BLEU points over three bi-text combinations of ML2EN and IN2EN), thus proving the potential of the idea.</text>
              <doc_id>234</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>We have further demonstrated the applicability of the general approach to other languages and domains.</text>
              <doc_id>235</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>In future work, we would like to add word deletion, insertion, splitting, and concatenation as allowed editing operations.</text>
              <doc_id>236</doc_id>
              <sec_id>3</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>We further want to explore tighter integration of word-based and phrasebased paraphrasing.</text>
              <doc_id>237</doc_id>
              <sec_id>4</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>Finally, we plan experiments with other language pairs and application to other linguistic problems.</text>
              <doc_id>238</doc_id>
              <sec_id>5</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
        </paragraphs>
        <subsections/>
      </section>
      <section>
        <index>9</index>
        <title>Acknowledgments</title>
        <text>We would like to give special thanks to Harta Wijaya and Aldrian Obaja Muis, native speakers of Indonesian, for their help in the linguistic analysis of the input and output of our system. We would also like to thank the anonymous reviewers for their constructive comments and suggestions, which have helped us improve the quality of this paper. This research is supported by the Singapore National Research Foundation under its International Research Centre @ Singapore Funding Initiative and administered by the IDM Programme Office.</text>
        <paragraphs>
          <paragraph>
            <sentence>
              <text>We would like to give special thanks to Harta Wijaya and Aldrian Obaja Muis, native speakers of Indonesian, for their help in the linguistic analysis of the input and output of our system.</text>
              <doc_id>239</doc_id>
              <sec_id>0</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>We would also like to thank the anonymous reviewers for their constructive comments and suggestions, which have helped us improve the quality of this paper.</text>
              <doc_id>240</doc_id>
              <sec_id>1</sec_id>
            </sentence>
            <sentence>
              <text>This research is supported by the Singapore National Research Foundation under its International Research Centre @ Singapore Funding Initiative and administered by the IDM Programme Office.</text>
              <doc_id>241</doc_id>
              <sec_id>2</sec_id>
            </sentence>
          </paragraph>
        </paragraphs>
        <subsections/>
      </section>
    </sections>
    <tables>
      <table>
        <id>1</id>
        <source>TableSeer</source>
        <caption>Table 1: The 10-best &#8220;Indonesian&#8221; sentences extracted from the confusion network in Figure 1.</caption>
        <reference_text>In PAGE 4: ... 5For balance, in case of less than n adaptations for a Malay sentence, we randomly repeat some of the available ones. 6According to a native Indonesian speaker, options 1 and 3 in  Table1  are perfect adaptations, options 2 and 5 have a wrong word order, and the rest are grammatical though not perfect. Moreover, the options we propose for a Malay word are inherently restricted to the small Indone- sian vocabulary of the Indonesian?English bi-text....</reference_text>
        <page_num>5</page_num>
        <head>
          <rows>
            <row>
              <cell>Rank</cell>
              <cell>&#8220;Indonesian&#8221; Sentence</cell>
              <cell>None</cell>
              <cell>Indonesian  Sentence</cell>
              <cell>Indonesian  Sentence</cell>
            </row>
          </rows>
        </head>
        <body>
          <rows>
            <row>
              <cell>1</cell>
              <cell>pdb</cell>
              <cell>malaysia</cell>
              <cell>akan</cell>
              <cell>mencapai 8 persen pada tahun 2010 .</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>2</cell>
              <cell>pdb</cell>
              <cell>malaysia</cell>
              <cell>untuk</cell>
              <cell>mencapai 8 persen pada tahun 2010 .</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>3</cell>
              <cell>pdb</cell>
              <cell>malaysia</cell>
              <cell>diperkirakan</cell>
              <cell>mencapai 8 persen pada tahun 2010 .</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>4</cell>
              <cell>maka</cell>
              <cell>malaysia</cell>
              <cell>akan</cell>
              <cell>mencapai 8 persen pada tahun 2010 .</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>5</cell>
              <cell>maka</cell>
              <cell>malaysia</cell>
              <cell>untuk</cell>
              <cell>mencapai 8 persen pada tahun 2010 .</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>6</cell>
              <cell>pdb</cell>
              <cell>malaysia</cell>
              <cell>dapat</cell>
              <cell>mencapai 8 persen pada tahun 2010 .</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>7</cell>
              <cell>maka</cell>
              <cell>malaysia</cell>
              <cell>diperkirakan</cell>
              <cell>mencapai 8 persen pada tahun 2010 .</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>8</cell>
              <cell>sebesar</cell>
              <cell>malaysia</cell>
              <cell>akan</cell>
              <cell>mencapai 8 persen pada tahun 2010 .</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>9</cell>
              <cell>pdb</cell>
              <cell>malaysia</cell>
              <cell>diharapkan</cell>
              <cell>mencapai 8 persen pada tahun 2010 .</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>10</cell>
              <cell>pdb</cell>
              <cell>malaysia</cell>
              <cell>ini</cell>
              <cell>mencapai 8 persen pada tahun 2010 .</cell>
            </row>
          </rows>
        </body>
      </table>
      <table>
        <id>2</id>
        <source>TET</source>
        <caption>Table 2: The five baselines. The subscript indicates the parameters found on IN2EN-dev and used for IN2EN-test. The scores that are statistically significantly better than ML2EN and IN2EN (p &lt; 0.01, Collins&#8217; sign test) are shown in bold and are underlined, respectively.</caption>
        <reference_text></reference_text>
        <page_num>6</page_num>
        <head>
          <rows>
            <row>
              <cell>System</cell>
              <cell>BLEU</cell>
            </row>
          </rows>
        </head>
        <body>
          <rows>
            <row>
              <cell>ML2EN</cell>
              <cell>14.50</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>IN2EN</cell>
              <cell>18.67</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>Simple concatenation</cell>
              <cell>18.49</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>Balanced concatenation</cell>
              <cell>19.79</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>Sophisticated phrase table combination</cell>
              <cell>20.10 (.5.5)</cell>
            </row>
          </rows>
        </body>
      </table>
      <table>
        <id>3</id>
        <source>TET</source>
        <caption>Table 3: Isolated experiments. The subscript shows the best tuning parameters, and the superscript shows the absolute test improvement over the ML2EN and the IN2EN baselines. The last line shows system combination results.</caption>
        <reference_text></reference_text>
        <page_num>7</page_num>
        <head>
          <rows>
            <row>
              <cell>n-gram precision</cell>
            </row>
          </rows>
        </head>
        <body>
          <rows>
            <row>
              <cell></cell>
              <cell>System</cell>
              <cell>1-gr.</cell>
              <cell>2-gr.</cell>
              <cell>3-gr.</cell>
              <cell>4-gr.</cell>
              <cell>BLEU</cell>
              <cell>TER</cell>
              <cell>METEOR</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell></cell>
              <cell>ML2EN (baseline)</cell>
              <cell>48.34</cell>
              <cell>19.22</cell>
              <cell>9.54</cell>
              <cell>4.98</cell>
              <cell>14.50</cell>
              <cell>67.14</cell>
              <cell>43.28</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell></cell>
              <cell>IN2EN (baseline)</cell>
              <cell>55.04</cell>
              <cell>23.90</cell>
              <cell>12.87</cell>
              <cell>7.18</cell>
              <cell>18.67</cell>
              <cell>61.99</cell>
              <cell>54.34</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell></cell>
              <cell>CN:pivot</cell>
              <cell>54.50</cell>
              <cell>24.41</cell>
              <cell>13.09</cell>
              <cell>7.35</cell>
              <cell>18.91 (+4.41,+0.24)
(0.005,10best)</cell>
              <cell>61.94</cell>
              <cell>51.07</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell></cell>
              <cell>CN:pivot &#8242;</cell>
              <cell>55.05</cell>
              <cell>25.09</cell>
              <cell>13.60</cell>
              <cell>7.69</cell>
              <cell>19.50 (+5.00,+0.83)
(0.001,10best)</cell>
              <cell>61.25</cell>
              <cell>51.97</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>(i)</cell>
              <cell>CN:pivot &#8242; +morph</cell>
              <cell>55.97</cell>
              <cell>25.73</cell>
              <cell>14.06</cell>
              <cell>7.99</cell>
              <cell>20.06 (+5.56,+1.39)
(0.005,10best)</cell>
              <cell>60.31</cell>
              <cell>55.65</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell></cell>
              <cell>PPT:1</cell>
              <cell>55.11</cell>
              <cell>25.04</cell>
              <cell>13.66</cell>
              <cell>7.80</cell>
              <cell>19.58 (+5.08,+0.91)
(10best)</cell>
              <cell>60.92</cell>
              <cell>51.93</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell></cell>
              <cell>PPT:4</cell>
              <cell>56.64</cell>
              <cell>26.20</cell>
              <cell>14.53</cell>
              <cell>8.40</cell>
              <cell>20.63 (+6.13,+1.96)
(10best)</cell>
              <cell>59.33</cell>
              <cell>54.23</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>(ii) PPT:4::CN:morph</cell>
              <cell>56.91</cell>
              <cell>26.53</cell>
              <cell>14.76</cell>
              <cell>8.55</cell>
              <cell>20.89 (+6.39,+2.22)
(10best)</cell>
              <cell>59.30</cell>
              <cell>57.19</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>System combination: (i) + (ii)</cell>
              <cell>57.73</cell>
              <cell>27.00</cell>
              <cell>15.03</cell>
              <cell>8.71</cell>
              <cell>21.24 (+6.74,+2.57)</cell>
              <cell>58.19</cell>
              <cell>54.63</cell>
            </row>
          </rows>
        </body>
      </table>
      <table>
        <id>4</id>
        <source>TableSeer</source>
        <caption>Table 4: Combined experiments: BLEU. The best tuning parameter values are in subscript, and the absolute test improvement over the corresponding baseline (on top of each column) is in superscript.</caption>
        <reference_text>In PAGE 8: ...aselines, which only achieve up to 20.10 BLEU. 6.3 Combined Experiments  Table4  shows the performance of the three bi- text combination strategies (see Section 4.3 for ad- ditional details) when applied to combine IN2EN (1) with the original ML2EN and (2) with various adapted versions of it....</reference_text>
        <page_num>8</page_num>
        <head>
          <rows>
            <row>
              <cell>Combination with</cell>
              <cell>Simple Concatenation</cell>
              <cell>Balanced Concatenation</cell>
              <cell>Sophisticated Combination</cell>
            </row>
          </rows>
        </head>
        <body>
          <rows>
            <row>
              <cell>+ ML2EN (unadapted</cell>
              <cell>baseline)</cell>
              <cell>18.49</cell>
              <cell>19.79</cell>
              <cell>20.10(.5.5)</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>+ CN:pivot</cell>
              <cell>19.99(+1.50)</cell>
              <cell>20.16(+0.37)</cell>
              <cell>20.32(+0.22)</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>None</cell>
              <cell>(0.001,1best) 20.03(+1.54)</cell>
              <cell>(0.001,10best) 20.80(+1.01)</cell>
              <cell>(0.01,10best,.5.5) 20.55(+0.45)</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>+ CN:pivot?</cell>
              <cell>(0.05,1best)</cell>
              <cell>(0.05,10best)</cell>
              <cell>(0.05,10best,.5.5)</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>(ii) + CN:pivot?+morph</cell>
              <cell>20.60(+2.11)</cell>
              <cell>21.15(+1.36)</cell>
              <cell>21.05(+0.95)</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>None</cell>
              <cell>(0.01,10best) 20.61(+2.12)</cell>
              <cell>(0.01,10best) 20.71(+0.92)</cell>
              <cell>(0.01,5best,00) 20.32(+0.22)</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>+ PPT:1</cell>
              <cell>(1best)</cell>
              <cell>(10best)</cell>
              <cell>(1best,000)</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>+ PPT:4</cell>
              <cell>20.75(+2.26)</cell>
              <cell>21.08(+1.29)</cell>
              <cell>20.76(+0.66)</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>None</cell>
              <cell>(1best) 21.01(+2.52)</cell>
              <cell>(5best) 21.31(+1.52)</cell>
              <cell>(10best,.5.5.5) 20.98(+0.88)</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>(iii) + PPT:4::CN:morph</cell>
              <cell>(1best)</cell>
              <cell>(5best)</cell>
              <cell>(10best,.5)</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>None</cell>
              <cell>21.55(+3.06)</cell>
              <cell>21.64(+1.85)</cell>
              <cell>21.62(+1.52)</cell>
            </row>
          </rows>
        </body>
      </table>
      <table>
        <id>6</id>
        <source>TableSeer</source>
        <caption>Table 6: Human judgments: Malay vs. &#8220;Indonesian&#8221;. The parameter values are those from Tables 3 and 5.</caption>
        <reference_text>In PAGE 9: ...N:pivot,t=0 vs. (b) CN:pivot?+morph. Since the latter is noisy, the top 3 choices were judged for it.  Table6  shows that CN:pivot,t=0 is better/equal to the original 53%/31% of the time. In contrast, CN:pivot?+morph is typically worse than the orig- inal; even compared to the best in top 3, the bet- ter:worse ratio is 45%:43%....</reference_text>
        <page_num>9</page_num>
        <head>
          <rows>
            <row>
              <cell>in a  bad  sentence.</cell>
              <cell>None</cell>
              <cell>None</cell>
              <cell></cell>
            </row>
          </rows>
        </head>
        <body>
          <rows>
            <row>
              <cell>System</cell>
              <cell>Better</cell>
              <cell>Equal</cell>
              <cell>Worse</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>CN:pivot, t = 0(Rank1)</cell>
              <cell>53%</cell>
              <cell>31%</cell>
              <cell>16%</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>CN:pivot?+morph(Rank1)</cell>
              <cell>38%</cell>
              <cell>8%</cell>
              <cell>54%</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>CN:pivot?+morph(Rank2)</cell>
              <cell>41%</cell>
              <cell>9%</cell>
              <cell>50%</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>CN:pivot?+morph(Rank3)</cell>
              <cell>32%</cell>
              <cell>11%</cell>
              <cell>57%</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>CN:pivot?+morph(Ranks:1?3)</cell>
              <cell>45%</cell>
              <cell>12%</cell>
              <cell>43%</cell>
            </row>
          </rows>
        </body>
      </table>
      <table>
        <id>7</id>
        <source>TET</source>
        <caption>Table 7: Reversed adaptation: Indonesian to Malay.</caption>
        <reference_text></reference_text>
        <page_num>9</page_num>
        <head>
          <rows>
            <row>
              <cell>System</cell>
              <cell>BLEU</cell>
            </row>
          </rows>
        </head>
        <body>
          <rows>
            <row>
              <cell>CN:pivot (Malay&#8594;Indonesian)</cell>
              <cell>18.91 (0.005,10best)</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>CN:pivot (Indonesian&#8594;Malay) &#8211; lattice</cell>
              <cell>17.22 (0.05)</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>CN:pivot (Indonesian&#8594;Malay) &#8211; 1-best</cell>
              <cell>17.77 (0.001)</cell>
            </row>
          </rows>
        </body>
      </table>
      <table>
        <id>8</id>
        <source>TableSeer</source>
        <caption>Table 8: Improving Macedonian&#8211;English SMT by adapting Bulgarian to Macedonian.</caption>
        <reference_text>In PAGE 10: ...2M Macedonian and 433M English words.  Table8  shows that both CN:* and PPT:* yield statistically significant improvements over balanced concatenation with unadapted BG2EN; system com- bination with MEMT improves even further. This indicates that our approach can work for other pairs of related languages and even for other domains....</reference_text>
        <page_num>10</page_num>
        <head>
          <rows>
            <row>
              <cell>System</cell>
              <cell>BLEU</cell>
              <cell>TER</cell>
              <cell>METEOR</cell>
            </row>
          </rows>
        </head>
        <body>
          <rows>
            <row>
              <cell>BG2EN (baseline)</cell>
              <cell>24.57</cell>
              <cell>57.64</cell>
              <cell>41.60</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>MK2EN (baseline)</cell>
              <cell>26.46</cell>
              <cell>54.55</cell>
              <cell>46.15</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>Balanced concatenation of MK2EN with an adapted BG2EN</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>+ BG2EN (unadapted)</cell>
              <cell>27.33</cell>
              <cell>54.61</cell>
              <cell>48.16</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>+ CN:pivot &#8242; +morph</cell>
              <cell>27.97 (+0.64,+1.51)</cell>
              <cell>54.08</cell>
              <cell>49.65</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>+ PPT:4::CN:morph</cell>
              <cell>28.38 (+1.05,+1.92)</cell>
              <cell>53.35</cell>
              <cell>48.21</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
              <cell>Combining last three</cell>
              <cell>29.05 (+1.72,+2.59)</cell>
              <cell>52.31</cell>
              <cell>50.96</cell>
            </row>
          </rows>
        </body>
      </table>
    </tables>
    <references>
      <reference>
        <id>0</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Kemal Altintas</author>
          <author>Ilyas Cicekli</author>
        </authors>
        <title>A machine translation system between a pair of closely related languages.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the 17th International Symposium on Computer and Information Sciences, ISCIS &#8217;02,</publication>
        <pages>192--196</pages>
        <date>2002</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>1</id>
        <authors>
          <author>AiTi Aw</author>
          <author>Min Zhang</author>
          <author>Juan Xiao</author>
          <author>Jian Su</author>
        </authors>
        <title>A phrase-based statistical model for SMS text normalization.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the 21st International Conference on Computational Linguistics and 44th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL-COLING &#8217;06.</publication>
        <pages>None</pages>
        <date>2006</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>2</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Abo Bakr</author>
          <author>Khaled Shaalan</author>
          <author>Ibrahim Ziedan</author>
        </authors>
        <title>A hybrid approach for converting written Egyptian colloquial dialect into diacritized Arabic.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on Informatics and Systems, INFOS &#8217;08.</publication>
        <pages>None</pages>
        <date>2008</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>3</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Timothy Baldwin</author>
          <author>Su&#8217;ad Awab</author>
        </authors>
        <title>Open source corpus analysis tools for Malay.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the 5th International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation, LREC &#8217;06,</publication>
        <pages>2212--2215</pages>
        <date>2006</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>4</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Alexandra Birch</author>
          <author>Miles Osborne</author>
          <author>Philipp Koehn</author>
        </authors>
        <title>CCG supertags in factored statistical machine translation.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the Second Workshop on Statistical Machine Translation, WMT &#8217;07,</publication>
        <pages>9--16</pages>
        <date>2007</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>5</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Chris Callison-Burch</author>
          <author>Philipp Koehn</author>
          <author>Miles Osborne</author>
        </authors>
        <title>Improved statistical machine translation using paraphrases.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the Human Language Technology Conference of NAACL, HLTNAACL &#8217;06,</publication>
        <pages>17--24</pages>
        <date>2006</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>6</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Trevor Cohn</author>
          <author>Mirella Lapata</author>
        </authors>
        <title>Machine translation by triangulation: Making effective use of multiparallel corpora.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the 45th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL &#8217;07,</publication>
        <pages>728--735</pages>
        <date>2007</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>7</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Michael Collins</author>
          <author>Philipp Koehn</author>
          <author>Ivona Ku&#269;erov&#225;</author>
        </authors>
        <title>Clause restructuring for statistical machine translation.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the 43rd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL &#8217;05,</publication>
        <pages>531--540</pages>
        <date>2005</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>8</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Jan Haji&#269;</author>
          <author>Jan Hric</author>
          <author>Vladislav Kubo&#328;</author>
        </authors>
        <title>Machine translation of very close languages.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the Sixth Conference on Applied Natural Language Processing, ANLP &#8217;00,</publication>
        <pages>7--12</pages>
        <date>2000</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>9</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Bo Han</author>
          <author>Timothy Baldwin</author>
        </authors>
        <title>Lexical normalisation of short text messages: Makn sens a #twitter.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies, ACL-HLT &#8217;11,</publication>
        <pages>368--378</pages>
        <date>2011</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>10</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Kenneth Heafield</author>
          <author>Alon Lavie</author>
        </authors>
        <title>Combining machine translation output with open source: The Carnegie Mellon multi-engine machine translation scheme.</title>
        <publication>The Prague Bulletin of Mathematical Linguistics,</publication>
        <pages>None</pages>
        <date>2010</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>11</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Lu&#237;s Marujo</author>
          <author>Nuno Grazina</author>
          <author>Tiago Lu&#237;s</author>
          <author>Wang Ling</author>
          <author>Lu&#237;sa Coheur</author>
          <author>Isabel Trancoso</author>
        </authors>
        <title>BP2EP -adaptation of Brazilian Portuguese texts to European Portuguese.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the 15th Conference of the European Association for Machine Translation, EAMT &#8217;11,</publication>
        <pages>129--136</pages>
        <date>2011</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>12</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Preslav Nakov</author>
          <author>Hwee Tou Ng</author>
        </authors>
        <title>Improved statistical machine translation for resource-poor languages using related resource-rich languages.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, EMNLP &#8217;09,</publication>
        <pages>1358--1367</pages>
        <date>2009</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>13</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Preslav Nakov</author>
          <author>Hwee Tou Ng</author>
        </authors>
        <title>Translating from morphologically complex languages: A paraphrase-based approach.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies, ACL-HLT &#8217;11,</publication>
        <pages>1298--1307</pages>
        <date>2011</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>14</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Preslav Nakov</author>
          <author>Hwee Tou Ng</author>
        </authors>
        <title>Improving statistical machine translation for a resource-poor language using related resource-rich languages.</title>
        <publication>None</publication>
        <pages>44--179</pages>
        <date>2012</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>15</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Preslav Nakov</author>
          <author>J&#246;rg Tiedemann</author>
        </authors>
        <title>Combining word-level and character-level models for machine translation between closely-related languages.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the 50th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL-Short &#8217;12.</publication>
        <pages>None</pages>
        <date>2012</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>16</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Kishore Papineni</author>
          <author>Salim Roukos</author>
          <author>Todd Ward</author>
          <author>WeiJing Zhu</author>
        </authors>
        <title>BLEU: a method for automatic evaluation of machine translation.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the 40th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics, ACL &#8217;02,</publication>
        <pages>311--318</pages>
        <date>2002</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>17</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Eric Ristad</author>
          <author>Peter Yianilos</author>
        </authors>
        <title>Learning stringedit distance.</title>
        <publication>None</publication>
        <pages>None</pages>
        <date>1998</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>18</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Wael Salloum</author>
          <author>Nizar Habash</author>
        </authors>
        <title>Dialectal to Standard Arabic paraphrasing to improve ArabicEnglish statistical machine translation.</title>
        <publication>In Proc. of the Workshop on Algorithms and Resources for Modelling of Dialects and Language Varieties,</publication>
        <pages>10--21</pages>
        <date>2011</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>19</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Hassan Sawaf</author>
        </authors>
        <title>Arabic dialect handling in hybrid machine translation.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the 9th Conference of the Association for Machine Translation in the Americas, AMTA &#8217;09.</publication>
        <pages>None</pages>
        <date>2010</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>20</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Kevin P Scannell</author>
        </authors>
        <title>Machine translation for closely related language pairs.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the LREC 2006 Workshop on Strategies for Developing Machine Translation for Minority Languages.</publication>
        <pages>None</pages>
        <date>2006</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>21</id>
        <authors>
          <author>J&#246;rg Tiedemann</author>
        </authors>
        <title>News from OPUS - a collection of multilingual parallel corpora with tools and interfaces.</title>
        <publication>In Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing,</publication>
        <pages>237--248</pages>
        <date>2009</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>22</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Masao Utiyama</author>
          <author>Hitoshi Isahara</author>
        </authors>
        <title>A comparison of pivot methods for phrase-based statistical machine translation.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the Human Language Technology Conference of NAACL, HLTNAACL &#8217;07,</publication>
        <pages>484--491</pages>
        <date>2007</date>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <id>23</id>
        <authors>
          <author>Hua Wu</author>
          <author>Haifeng Wang</author>
        </authors>
        <title>Revisiting pivot language approach for machine translation.</title>
        <publication>In Proceedings of the Joint Conference of the 47th Annual Meeting of the ACL, ACL &#8217;09,</publication>
        <pages>154--162</pages>
        <date>2009</date>
      </reference>
    </references>
    <citations>
      <citation>
        <id>0</id>
        <reference_id>0</reference_id>
        <string>Altintas and Cicekli, 2002</string>
        <sentence_id>12554</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>120</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>1</id>
        <reference_id>1</reference_id>
        <string>Aw et al., 2006</string>
        <sentence_id>12561</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>128</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>2</id>
        <reference_id>2</reference_id>
        <string>Bakr et al., 2008</string>
        <sentence_id>12556</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>310</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>3</id>
        <reference_id>3</reference_id>
        <string>Baldwin and Awab (2006)</string>
        <sentence_id>12638</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>88</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>4</id>
        <reference_id>4</reference_id>
        <string>Birch et al., 2007</string>
        <sentence_id>12671</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>94</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>5</id>
        <reference_id>5</reference_id>
        <string>Callison-Burch et al., 2006</string>
        <sentence_id>12610</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>11</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>6</id>
        <reference_id>6</reference_id>
        <string>Cohn and Lapata, 2007</string>
        <sentence_id>12573</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>141</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>7</id>
        <reference_id>7</reference_id>
        <string>Collins et al. (2005)</string>
        <sentence_id>12728</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>80</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>8</id>
        <reference_id>8</reference_id>
        <string>Haji&#269; et al., 2000</string>
        <sentence_id>12554</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>75</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>9</id>
        <reference_id>9</reference_id>
        <string>Han and Baldwin, 2011</string>
        <sentence_id>12561</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>145</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>10</id>
        <reference_id>10</reference_id>
        <string>Heafield and Lavie, 2010</string>
        <sentence_id>12720</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>91</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>11</id>
        <reference_id>11</reference_id>
        <string>Marujo et al. (2011)</string>
        <sentence_id>12566</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>13</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>12</id>
        <reference_id>12</reference_id>
        <string>Nakov and Ng, 2009</string>
        <sentence_id>12546</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>198</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>13</id>
        <reference_id>12</reference_id>
        <string>Nakov and Ng, 2009</string>
        <sentence_id>12570</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>32</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>14</id>
        <reference_id>12</reference_id>
        <string>Nakov and Ng, 2009</string>
        <sentence_id>12664</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>78</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>15</id>
        <reference_id>12</reference_id>
        <string>Nakov and Ng, 2009</string>
        <sentence_id>12671</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>298</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>16</id>
        <reference_id>13</reference_id>
        <string>Nakov and Ng, 2011</string>
        <sentence_id>12649</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>170</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>17</id>
        <reference_id>14</reference_id>
        <string>Nakov and Ng, 2012</string>
        <sentence_id>12546</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>218</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>18</id>
        <reference_id>14</reference_id>
        <string>Nakov and Ng, 2012</string>
        <sentence_id>12570</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>52</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>19</id>
        <reference_id>14</reference_id>
        <string>Nakov and Ng, 2012</string>
        <sentence_id>12664</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>98</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>20</id>
        <reference_id>14</reference_id>
        <string>Nakov and Ng, 2012</string>
        <sentence_id>12671</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>318</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>21</id>
        <reference_id>15</reference_id>
        <string>Nakov and Tiedemann, 2012</string>
        <sentence_id>12554</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>217</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>22</id>
        <reference_id>16</reference_id>
        <string>Papineni et al., 2002</string>
        <sentence_id>12692</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>95</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>23</id>
        <reference_id>17</reference_id>
        <string>Ristad and Yianilos, 1998</string>
        <sentence_id>12645</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>166</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>24</id>
        <reference_id>18</reference_id>
        <string>Salloum and Habash, 2011</string>
        <sentence_id>12556</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>342</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>25</id>
        <reference_id>19</reference_id>
        <string>Sawaf, 2010</string>
        <sentence_id>12556</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>329</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>26</id>
        <reference_id>20</reference_id>
        <string>Scannell, 2006</string>
        <sentence_id>12554</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>173</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>27</id>
        <reference_id>21</reference_id>
        <string>Tiedemann, 2009</string>
        <sentence_id>12757</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>188</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>28</id>
        <reference_id>22</reference_id>
        <string>Utiyama and Isahara, 2007</string>
        <sentence_id>12573</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>114</char_offset>
      </citation>
      <citation>
        <id>29</id>
        <reference_id>23</reference_id>
        <string>Wu and Wang, 2009</string>
        <sentence_id>12573</sentence_id>
        <char_offset>164</char_offset>
      </citation>
    </citations>
  </content>
</document>
